Chapter 2: The Interview Pt 1

Updated 11/04/2011

"I notice that I am confused."

=ooo=

Lunch was nearly over. James Monroe was still finishing the last bit of filet mignon on his plate. Harry Potter-Evans-Verres had finished his meal and was sitting across the table from the journalist, seemingly lost in thought as he sipped absently at a crystal goblet filled with wine.

Monroe expected Harry was organizing his thoughts, contemplating the questions he would be asked during the interview. Most of the questions were well-known: What is the Singularity and Is the Singularity near, stuff like that, all pretty standard questions for an interview. Monroe hoped to challenge Harry with a few hard questions, dealing with information Monroe had collected about TBC Enterprises over the past few months he'd been trying to get this meeting.

Almost the moment Monroe dropped the fork on his empty plate, a server appeared from the second door, removing their dishes and returning with coffee cups. Monroe nodded as the young woman offered to fill his cup; she filled Harry's without asking. The server also left a small tray with sugar packets, substitute, and creamer. Harry helped himself to a couple of sugar packets and the creamer, while Monroe used a substitute and a small splash of creamer. For several moments the only sounds in the room were spoons clinking as they stirred their drinks.

"Anytime you're ready," Harry finally said, glancing at his watch.

Monroe reached into his inside jacket pocket and took out a pen. However, he did not take out a notepad; instead, he clicked the pen and placed it between them on the table. Harry gazed at the object with interest.

"A recording device?" he asked, looking up at Monroe.

"Audio only," Monroe nodded. "I didn't think you'd mind — it's for both of our protection. I'll let you have a copy of the recording, I can download it into an MP3 device if you have one that accepts Bluetooth V protocols."

"That's acceptable," Harry agreed. "In fact —" he reached into a pocket and took out a device that looked like a flash drive, but without the mini-USB port. "This is a similar device manufactured by one of our subsidiary companies. It has 128 gigabytes of recording memory and can produce most of the major audio formats, uploadable through BT5 to any device that can play back any of the formats."

Monroe looked fascinatedly at the device. "Impressive! My Record-A-Pen only has 64 gigs, and only uploads MP3's. I guess I'm not on the cutting edge of technology these days."

"Apparently not," Harry agreed, in a neutral tone. He tapped his recording device and a small red LED began blinking. "Ready when you are, Gridley."

Monroe smiled at the odd reference. Harry was apparently well-read. "Let's start with the most obvious question: What does the Singularity mean to you?"

"The end of my job, obviously," Harry grinned. "But that's probably not the response your audience would expect. I'd say it's a time in future history of radical change, when progress occurs faster than normal humans can understand, or keep up with."

A boilerplate response, thought Monroe. "Any ideas what type of progress you think will most likely produce this radical change?" he asked.

"Oh…" Harry looked thoughtful for several seconds, sipping his coffee. "I'm not sure. It's kind of a toss-up which way the tech research companies decide are the coolest, or maybe the least nerdy."

Nicely evaded. "Which way do you think is least nerdy?" Monroe pressed.

Harry cocked his head. "I think brain-computer interfaces will be the most interesting. We have a subsidiary working on that."

"Which one?" Monroe asked.

Harry only smiled and took another sip.

Okay, Monroe thought. Let's move on, then. "Do you think the Singularity is near?"

"It depends on what you mean by 'near,'" Harry answered, and Monroe suppressed a sigh of exasperation. It's like pulling teeth to get this guy to talk.

"Whatever you consider near," Monroe suggested.

Harry steepled his fingers on the table once again. "I like Kurzweil's prediction of 2045," he said. "It's out far enough to give the AI people a chance to develop human-level intelligence without being overly optimistic about it."

"What do you consider 'overly optimistic'?" Monroe continued.

"Oh, 2020, 2030, estimates like that." Harry waved a hand dismissing them.

"Why consider them optimistic?"

"There's still a lot to be done," Harry answered. "Even I have fallen prey to the planning fallacy in the past. In 1956 scientists at the Dartmouth Conference on Artificial Intelligence suggested, in all seriousness, that key elements of artificial intelligence could be solved by ten scientists working on them for about two months. Here we are, 60 years later, and they are just barely starting to understand what must still be done."

"You're starting to come off as something of a skeptic," Monroe remarked, taking a drink from his own cup, the first one he'd had since it had been filled.

"Not at all," Harry disagreed. "I think they simply failed to grasp the scope of the problem. Self-improving AI is just a stepping-stone to the Singularity itself."

"What is TBC doing to work toward the Singularity?" was Monroe's next question.

"We're primarily going down the 'N' path of the GNR paradigm," Harry responded. "Currently our primary product development is in MEMS, and we've been doing cutting-edge research in grapheme IC's, diamond manufacturing for quantum computer systems, and self-repairing and assembling nanosystems."

"How far are we away from molecular nanotechnology, the so-called 'Holy Grail' of nanotech?"

"Less than a decade, I would estimate," Harry said. "It will probably be developed before human-level AI becomes available."

"Some scientists consider MNT to be problematic without better-than-human level intelligence to control it," Monroe pointed out. "What do you think of that?"

Harry shrugged. "It's the same problem the 'Friendly-AI' people have with uncontrolled development of smarter-than-human machine intelligence.

"So, how long until we have human-level Artificial Intelligence?" Monroe pressed.

"Well, Kurzweil's prediction for a machine to pass the Turing test is by 2029," Harry answered. "I'd agree with that, for the most part."

"For the most part?" Monroe echoed. "Are any of your 'subsidiaries' working on AI now?"

Harry smiled thinly at the obvious quotes Monroe put around the word "subsidiary." "We have some research going on," he admitted. "I'm not really at liberty to discuss specifics."

Monroe was silent for several seconds. Potter was talking a lot but not really saying much positive about the Singularity. He took a few sips of his coffee, then asked, "Do you think the Singularity should be a cause for alarm or concern for people?"

Harry chuckled briefly. "I don't think most people are even going to know the Singularity occurred, much less be alarmed over it."

Monroe frowned. That was interesting. And alarming in itself, in a way. "I would think everyone would know about the Singularity, when it occurred."

"Yes, you might think that," Harry agreed, dryly. "But didn't we already agree earlier that the Singularity would be beyond most people's ability to comprehend? When you're confronted with an unknown, your only two real options are to try to comprehend it, or ignore it and hope it goes away. I think most people will do the latter."

Monroe shook his head. "I don't think I agreed to that at all."

"Then why didn't you call me on it when I said it, earlier?" Harry asked.

"Because I'm conducting an interview," Monroe pointed out, with a hint of acerbity in his voice. "I don't want to introduce bias into the conversation."

"Oh, so you admit you're biased when it comes to the Singularity, then."

Monroe's mouth clamped shut on the obscenity he almost uttered. Manipulative sonofabitch, isn't he? "I just don't want to interject my personal views into what you're saying," he answered, tightly.

"Why not?" Harry wondered, eyebrows raised in a falsely-innocent expression. "Won't you do that back at your offices when you're writing the story? I just don't expect most people to realize that the Singularity has occurred. In fact, how do we know it hasn't occurred yet?"

"That seems pretty obvious —" Monroe stopped, considering.

"I think you're seeing my point," Harry observed, and drained the last of his cup. He set the cup down and leaned forward over the table, toward Monroe. "In principle, we would not be able to tell the difference between reality and a perfect emulation of reality."

"Like that movie, The Matrix," Monroe suggested.

"I was thinking a bit more current," Harry said. "The Matrix is 17 years old, and the emulation wasn't perfect. People who learned they were in the Matrix found ways to bend the rules of the emulation, or break them. I was thinking more of the movie The Rainbow Reality."

The Rainbow Reality was a film that had come out last year. In it, the main protagonist, Bill, learned that the reality he was in was virtual when someone from the next lower level somehow passed that information to him. He had been in the Red Level, the highest level of implementation, and he embarked on a quest to find the lowest level, designated the Violet Level. Each level had had its own rules and its own exceptions to the rules — in the level Bill was in, he was a retired assassin who trained other assassins (mostly women) and sent them on assignments. His doppelganger in the Orange Level, suspecting that one of his assassins would return and kill him, had sent Bill a clue that allowed him to figure out a way to download himself to the Orange Level. The rest of the movie was a weird combination of angst and action as Bill found versions of himself — or those who had killed him — on every level.

"Those emulations weren't perfect, either," Monroe pointed out. "People could move from one level to another."

"If someone at a lower level told them a lower level existed," Harry argued. "But there was no internal rule-breaking at any of the levels, just the laws of physics as they were implemented for that level."

"Which always included a way to move to higher or lower levels," Monroe added.

"Don't you think we'll be able to do that after the Singularity?" Harry asked, curious. "Move to higher or lower levels of reality if we want to?"

"What level of reality do you think we're at now?" Monroe answered the question with one of his own. He was beginning to get tired of Harry Potter-Evans-Verres driving the interview in whatever direction he wanted.

"I'll answer," Harry said, after a moment. "If you promise to do the same."

Monroe sighed. "Very well," he said stiffly, silently resolving this was the last manipulation he would put up with. "I agree."

"My answer," Harry said at once. "Is that I think we always act as if we are at the lowest level of implementation, because, well, what other choice do we have?

"Your turn," Harry nodded to the journalist.

Monroe was silent for several moments. "My answer," he said at last. "Is the same as yours."

Harry actually giggled. "Now who's being manipulative?" he asked.

"That's not being manipulative!" Monroe said, sharply. "Aren't other people allowed to think the same way you do?"

"See?" Harry pointed toward him. "That's manipulation."

Monroe sat back suddenly in his chair. "This conversation is becoming surreal," he muttered, rubbing his forehead in frustration.

"Then my work here is nearly done," Harry grinned. "I like introducing as much surreality in people's lives as possible. And we haven't even gotten to the extraction of that mnemonic from your unconscious."

Monroe shook his head. "No, I don't think we're doing that any more."

"Oh, come on," Harry wheedled. "You're going to find it very interesting, I think."

"It's easy enough to say that," Monroe retorted. "But the reality is, your opinion of what I find interesting may not be that reliable. For example, this interview would have been much more interesting if you'd just answered the questions straightforwardly and not bobbed and weaved around everything I asked you, even if it hadn't been for all the work you put me through just to get to this point."

"I wanted to see how interested you were in this interview," Harry said, then shrugged. "Well, that was a lie. I really didn't want to do this interview in the first place, not for some paper magazine with a limited readership, even if you do upload your articles to the web these days. It just wasn't worth my time."

"So why did you do the interview?" Monroe asked, in a controlled tone. If for no other reason, Potter admitting that on the record would be very interesting reading — worth all the trouble it had taken him to get here.

"It was that recognition code," Harry answered. "It's the exact same phrase I used when I was a kid, to help me remember that I'd forgotten something. I'm really, really curious how you happened to come across it."

"I told you," Monroe was shaking his head. "I have no idea how I know —"

Harry interrupted him. "Would you like to know a really big secret?"

=ooo=

Very few witches or wizards, within the Ministry or without, knew the password that would admit them to the office of the Minister of Magic. The door to that office, securely locked and magically protected, suddenly burst open, admitting the Head of the Magical Law Enforcement Department, rage written across his sharp, pointed features. He stopped in front of the Minister's desk, barely controlling himself.

"What the hell does Harry think he's doing now?"

The Minister looked up at him. "Just as you and I think, most likely — he's having an interview with a Muggle journalist about something called the Singularity."

"Have you been watching what he's doing?" The Head Auror demanded.

"I have other things to do than watch Harry give an interview," the Minister said, mildly. "Besides, that's your job, Draco. You wanted those viewing devices planted in his office and private dining room."

"You told him about them!" Draco said, accusingly.

"I did not," the Minister shook her head. "You put the security level of those viewing devices above Harry's need to know, and I agreed with it, even though it would seem we don't trust him as much as say we do to his face. I have a problem with that, but Harry is privy to a lot of sensitive information — we do have to make sure it is kept out of the wrong hands."

"Watch this, then," Draco pointed his wand at the white display square on the Minister's desk, and the image of Harry and Muggle journalist appeared on it.

"It was that recognition code," Harry's image was saying. "It's the exact same phrase I used when I was a kid, to help me remember that I'd forgotten something. I'm really, really curious how you happened to come across it."

"I told you," the Muggle was shaking his head. "I have no idea how I know —"

Harry interrupted him. "Would you like to know a really big secret?"

And the image went blank.

Draco glared at the Minister. "What kind of 'really big secret' would Harry tell to a Muggle?"

The Minister was frowning at the blank screen. "I don't know," she said. "Surely not —"

"I'd like to believe that, too," Draco nodded. "After all this time, the existence of the Wizarding world is known to very few Muggles; most of them have witches and wizards as relatives. But —" he pointed to the blank display "— the feed cut off at that moment — we have no idea what Harry is telling him right now!"

The Minister sat back, a worried frown creasing her brow for the first time since Malfoy had entered her office. "I cannot believe Harry would willfully disregard the International Statute of Wizarding Secrecy just to find out what some Muggle knows about a memory code phrase he used as a kid. Was there anything this Muggle said that would indicate he already knows about magic?"

"Nothing," Draco shook his head sharply. "He seems completely clueless. In fact, the Thomas woman had Obliviated him after he stormed into Harry's office demanding to be heard. She was about to have him escorted out when he suddenly said, 'Recognition code 927, I am a potato,' which Harry overheard and invited him into his office for the interview. The Thomas woman —"

"You can call her Ginny," the Minister interrupted, mildly. "You've known her long enough, after all."

"The Thomas woman," Draco continued as if he hadn't heard, "went to lunch right after that, to have lunch with her brother Ron —"

"I know that," the Minister interrupted in turn. "I saw them in Diagon Alley when I stepped out for a quick bite. How is that relevant?"

"She is supposed to be keeping an eye on him for us," Draco gritted icily.

"Is she supposed to go hungry while she does that?" Hermione asked, just as coldly.

Draco simmered in impotent rage. "She might've had lunch brought up to her," he said. "But fine — you don't share my opinion on the obligations of those working for us."

"I don't share your distrust of Harry," Hermione smiled at him, making Draco even more angry, though he would never show such anger towards the Minister of Magic over her husband. Such would not be prudent, especially in his line of work, as dangerous as it was. Hermione Granger-Potter might be Minister of Magic, but she was still a mudblood, no matter what Harry Potter had proven to him about blood purity and magic. It was beyond that, anyway — who knew where her loyalties lay these days. She might even be in on this plot to let the Muggles know about the Wizarding World.

Sometimes, Draco wished he had never met Harry Potter, or let him teach Draco the ways of rationality, no matter what it had helped Draco accomplish over the past two decades.

Into his silence, Hermione leaned forward over her desk, her eyes staring into his. "Now, was there a point to you bursting into my office, Draco, or must I guess what you want me to do about this?"

"I'm going to contact Harry's director of operations and see what he suspects about what's going on," Draco answered.

"You don't need me for that," Hermione pointed out. "So you're saying that you burst in here just because you had no idea what Harry was doing, and you wanted me to give you some insight into his thinking, because we're married?"

"No," Draco said. Even though that was the reason he was here. "I wanted you to be aware that your husband may be very close to breaking international Wizarding law."

"Then you should go and make sure the Auror Department can prove that to the Wizengamot," Hermione suggested, dryly. She then looked away from Draco, back at what she'd been doing before he entered her office. "And close the door on your way out, please."

After a moment Draco nodded, stiffly, then strode silently to the door, pulling it shut after him. Hermione took out her wand, pointed it at the door, and said, "Colloportus," followed by several additional spells that she only used when she needed a very private conversation with her husband. Whatever Harry was up to, she needed to let him know that the Aurors were looking very closely at him (and probably at her as well — there were some downsides to having someone like Draco Malfoy running the Auror Department.

=ooo=

"A secret?" Monroe looked interested despite himself. "As a journalist, you should know that my primary objective is to expose secrets, not engage in keeping them."

Harry smiled evilly. "I'm sure you go around exposing your own secrets all the time, then, Mr. Monroe."

"That's different," Monroe retorted. "Of course everyone has secrets they would rather not have anyone know."

"Would you like to trade, one of mine for one of yours?" Harry asked, then waved off the look of indignation on Monroe's face. "I'm just kidding. But not about my secret. I do want to know where you heard that recognition code, but I have to show you a few things first before we get to that. I want you to understand that you'll be perfectly safe while we figure that out." Harry stood and walked to the wall of the private dining area furthest from the door they entered, then gestured for Monroe to join him as he took something from one of his pockets. Curious, Monroe picked up his recording pen from the table then stepped closer, watching as Harry waved the object, a long piece of thin wood, at the wall. A moment later Monroe caught his breath in stunned surprise.

A rectangular section of the wall sank inward, then slid to one side, revealing a much larger area beyond. "My private work area," Harry said, putting away the stick of wood into a pocket that looked too small to hold it. For that matter, Monroe remembered, he was sure Harry's office had been on a corner of the building they were in — where was the room for this workspace coming from?

The room must've been the size of a football field (perhaps he should say, soccer field, since the room was nearly as wide as it was long) over a hundred yards long and 80 to 90 yards wide. It looked to be perhaps 15 to 20 yards to the ceiling, from which long arrays of lights had turned on as the door opened, illuminating the entire area. There were dozens of workbenches scattered throughout the room, some with easily recognizable devices on them such as oscilloscopes, digital signal generators, and Fourier analyzers. Other benches had much weirder items on them — silver or gold mechanisms that spun or reciprocated, disgorging bursts of smoke or steam in odd patterns. Monroe could hear a dizzying cacophony of beeps, burps, toots, and even glorps, goops and splurts coming from nearly every bench near them.

He turned to Harry in utter confusion. "What the hell do you do in here?"

Harry was grinning a conspiratorial grin. "That's part of the big secret I've got for you, to show you what goes on in here." But when Monroe started into the room, Harry put a hand on his shoulder, stopping him. "That is, if we have an agreement that you'll let me figure out where you heard that recognition code. Deal or no deal?"

Monroe, now intensely curious what was going on in Harry's vast workroom, nevertheless gave him an apprehensive look. "What if some goon squad stops me on my way out of here afterwards, and takes my Record-A-Pen away from me? Then you've got my proof that any of this happened." He patted the Pen, now in his jacket pocket.

"You have my word that no one will take your pen away from you," Harry promised. He even put one hand in the air, as if he were formally swearing to that fact.

Monroe nodded, seemingly convinced. Even if Potter was lying, he knew, he had an ace up his sleeve — literally, as a backup recording device was sown into the lining of his jacket, much more sophisticated electronics device capable of picking up sounds up to a hundred yards away, using his entire jacket as a omnidirectional microphone. It was shielded as well, as an RFID device, so even if Potter's bug detectors picked it up they would think it was harmless.

"Okay, then," he answered. "It's a deal." He extended his hand, and Harry shook it. Now let's see whether he'll keep this deal, Monroe thought to himself.

"Come on in," Harry gestured for Monroe to follow as he stepped into the workroom. "Let's see," he pondered, looking around slowly. "How can I explain what I'm doing in here? Hmm. Ah!" He pointed to a nearby workbench. "There's just the thing, something I came up with a few years ago for the Ministry, though they decided not to use it."

Monroe followed Harry to a nearby workbench, where Harry picked up a cylindrical object from the bench and handed it to Monroe. "What do you think that is?" he asked.

Monroe examined the item carefully. It was a metal cylinder about a foot long, surprisingly lightweight for its size, with rounded ridges along the length of the cylinder, presumably for a better grip. There were a couple of switches near the top, one a toggle and the other a short slider. There was also a small readout near the top. Remaining Battery life? Monroe flipped the cylinder around so he could look at the top. He expected to find a lens and bulb, but there was only a translucent white covering there, slightly concave. To direct the beam better? "Is it a flashlight —?" Monroe began, his finger reaching for the toggle.

Harry reached out and blocked his thumb from flipping the toggle, pulling the object out of his hand. "Wrong guess," he said. "And you don't want this pointing at your head when you turn it on, by the way." He pointed the cylinder away from both of them, into empty air, and flipped the switch.

A beam of golden light extended from the end of the cylinder, reaching twice the length of the cylinder before abruptly stopping. Monroe stared at it, mouth agape, as Harry waved it momentarily. A humming sound came from the blade, its pitch rising and falling as Harry he moved it. "What does this remind you of?" Harry asked, expectantly.

"It's — it's a light saber," Monroe muttered, almost in shock. "But — you can't do that with lasers! They're a beam of light, not a solid object with a specific length! How can you be doing that?"

"Magic," Harry said, happily. He switched the toggle again and the beam disappeared. "You're right — science could never do something like that. But magic has no such restrictions."

"Magic…" Monroe looked utterly baffled by what Harry had just said. "You mean magic magic, not Keith Barry or David Blaine magic, right?" His vision was beginning to gray out — this was utterly beyond anything that had ever happened to him before. He looked around for a chair to sit on, and one was suddenly at his side. He plopped down in it, holding his head, which was still whirling with the idea of a magical light saber. He looked up at last, mustering his calm and rationality once again. "I'm still not sure about this," he said. "Because it's possible you could be fooling me about that light saber somehow, you know."

"Well, let's try something else, then," Harry said, taking out the wooden stick he'd put in his pocket a minute ago. He waved it at Monroe. "Wingardium Leviosa!" Monroe rose out of the chair about a foot in the air, still in sitting position.

"Holy crap!" Monroe shouted. "Am I floating?"

"Did I have a chance to attach any wires to you?" Harry asked. "I don't think —" There was a short buzzing sound, like a cell phone. "Just a second," he said. "I have to take this." He reached into a pocket and took out a small rectangular object, putting it to his ear. At the same time his wand made a quick series of movements while still pointed at the journalist. Monroe, meanwhile, was looking around himself in near panic, trying to figure out what was holding him up. He looked down at Harry and said, "—-" but nothing came out.

"Oh, hello, love," Harry said, smiling as he spoke into the phone. "Yes, I'm still doing the interview… No, not at all, nothing like that! He is? Well, he's always suspicious of me — probably just jealous I'm a captain of industry and he's a government employee… Yes, dear, I know you're one too, I was just… Yes, you're right, I'm sorry… Okay, love, see you this evening. Bye. Love you too, bye."

Harry put away the phone as Monroe was lowered to the floor. He put his hand to his throat. "Testing, one, two, three," he said, then glowered at Harry. "I tried to say something while you were on the phone but I couldn't! What did you do to me? More magic?"

"I couldn't have you spilling the beans while I was talking with my wife," Harry answered, as he slid the wooden stick he was holding back into a pocket that was still clearly too small to hold it. "She thinks we're just having a regular interview."

Monroe made a quick deduction. "You're not supposed to be telling me any of this, are you? That's why nobody ever heard of this — this magic or people who could…perform it…" That was a pretty big implication, if true. How many people were there out there, who could do this kind of stuff?

Harry made a gesture of indifference. "There are some among us who think that people knowing that real magic exists will bring about chaos and distrust among magical and non-magical people, and eventually destroy us all. I happen to think people are smarter than that, though."

"But telling me?" Monroe looked skeptical. "I'm just a writer for some Singularity magazine, not even one of the major players in the field. Why would you pick me to deliver this news to the world? I notice that I am confused."

Harry jerked, startled. "What did you just say?"

"I notice that I am confused," Monroe repeated. "People are more often confused by fiction than they are by facts —"

"You're doing it again!" Harry almost shouted. "I'd almost think we read the same authors, except that I've never heard that recognition code mnemonic anywhere except when I said it! I really have to know how you heard that."

"I guess we ought to discuss that, then," Monroe suggested. "Just how are you going to 'magic' that memory out of my head?"

"It's pretty simple," Harry said. "I have a device that we can use to view your memories of —" Harry stopped as a buzzer abruptly sounded. "Now what?" he muttered, through clenched teeth. "It seems like nobody trusts me these days!"

"What is it," Monroe asked, then stepped back involuntarily as Harry pulled out his wooden stick again, pointing it at him.

"Sorry," Harry said. "I have to hide you. Unavoidable — I'll be back in a minute or so."

Even as Monroe shook his head to stop Harry from magicking him again, his body suddenly stiffened, his arms snapping down to his sides. He began to tip over, and though Monroe tried to cry out in alarm no sound came from his mouth.

Before he hit the floor, however, his body suddenly stopped, then continued rotating until he was floating in the air again, this time face up. The buzzer sounded again, this time somehow more insistently. Harry floated Monroe onto an empty bench top, and everything suddenly went silent. A moment later Harry had covered Monroe with a silvery, semi-transparent material, then walked away.

How was this hiding him? Monroe wondered. Wouldn't a man-sized object covered with a silver sheet be pretty noticeable?

Harry walked over to the workroom's exit, waving his wand at the door, which slid open. On the other side was his Operations Director, Dean Thomas. "Harry," he nodded at him, casually. "How're things going today?"

"Never better! Harry replied, brightly. "What can I do for you, Dean?"

"Head Auror Malfoy just sent me a note, sir," Dean told him. "He said they noticed at the Ministry that that journalist, James Monroe, who entered the building before lunch this morning still hasn't left."

"He hasn't," Harry agreed. "We're still conducting the interview."

"Where is he?" Dean asked, leaning forward slightly to glance around the room. Harry made no move to prevent him. "He's not in here, is he, Harry?"

"Why would he be in here, Dean?" Harry asked, innocence written all over his face. "He's just a Muggle — he has no reason to know about magic."

"Well —" Dean hesitated a moment. "There was something about a recognition code…"

Harry raised an eyebrow. "Oh? Have you been talking to Ginny during lunch?"

"Uh, no…" Dean began. Was Ginny in on what Malfoy suspected Harry was doing? He certainly hoped not! Malfoy was a good Head Auror, but he did have a tendency toward vindictiveness, especially against former Gryffindors. Not to mention Harry as well. "I haven't seen her since we got to the office this morning…"

"That's what I thought," Harry nodded, in a musing tone. "Well, tell Malfoy that he's still here with me, and we'll be finishing up the interview in an hour or so. Tell him I'm finding it quite fascination, much more interesting than I expected it would be. That should really twist his tail."

Dean grinned. "I expect it will, sir. Thank you." The door slid shut. Harry shook his head once, then went back to the work bench where Monroe lay paralyzed by the Petrificus Totalus curse. He pulled the silvery covering off the journalist, then pointed his wand at Monroe's motionless form and said, "Finite Incatatem."

After a moment Monroe, realizing he could move again, sat up on the bench and glared angrily at Harry. "What was that about?" he shouted. "I couldn't move or hear a thing!"

"For you own protection," Harry said. "Or rather, mine, since you're not supposed to be in here. If my Operations Director saw you in here he'd be duty-bound to report me to the Ministry or face charges himself of conspiracy, and there's no point to letting anyone except me get in trouble for this."

"You might have mentioned that before you brought me in here!" Monroe said, loudly.

"On the other hand, you should be convinced by now that magic is real, am I right about that?" Harry pointed out.

"Well…yeah, I suppose," Monroe admitted.

"Good," Harry said, turning and gesturing for Monroe to follow him. He led the Muggle to a far corner of the workroom, where a tall, black cabinet stood against a wall with a square table a few yards from it. Opening the cabinet with a wave of his wand, Harry took out a shallow stone bowl, with odd-looking symbols carved around its lip, and placed it on the table between him and Monroe. Inside the bowl Monroe could see a swirling silvery essence, like light made liquid. He looked up at Harry.

"What — what is this thing?"

"This, Mr. Monroe," Harry said with a smile. "Is a Pensieve."

Chapter 5: The Lords of Chaos Ride Again

Updated 12/16/2011

"Chaos Lords, Evermore, yes we are!"

=ooo=

While Mary's Place afforded fine eating and a secure environment (Mary's Room) for sensitive conversations, there were other places in Diagon Alley that were equally secure, if not more so.

A case in point was a shop situated almost at the end of Diagon Alley — number 93, the location of Weaselys' Wizard Wheezes, operated by Fred, George and Ron Weasley, and their wives. The three wives, Verity, Angelina, and Luna, were at that moment running the noisy, bustling business while their husbands "slacked off," at least to their way of thinking, in a lunch meeting with Harry Potter-Evans-Verres, held in the infamous "Chaos Room" on the first floor of the building, just below their three personal apartments.

The room was now locked down and warded with no less than thirty-four protection spells, making the room even more secure than the private dining area at Mary's Place. Four robed, hooded and masked figures sat around a plain wooden table enjoying a feast of fish and chips, along with foamy mugs of Merlin's Best Mead, their masks pushed up enough to allow them to eat unimpeded. No one had spoken since the meal had begun, since all of the four Lords of Chaos had learned the importance of finishing their meals, which somehow never seemed to happen if they began speaking before the food was gone.

Each mask worn by the Lords was expressive of its owner's temperament. Two of the masks were golden in color, both of them at the moment displaying the smiling face of Comedy. These two masks held an enchantment that caused their expressions to change with the feelings and emotions of their wearing. More often than not, both masks would change at same time.

The third mask, worn by the youngest Weasley brother, was long and white, with sad black eyes and a long, open mouth, from the wearer's favorite character, Ghostface from the Scream movies. That mask was now pushed to one side as its wearer hungrily devoured the planks of deep-fried cod in front of him, washing down his meal with gulps of mead.

The fourth and final mask was white as well, with a reddish stain surrounding the wide, grinning mouth of the mask and blackened stains around the eyeholes, representing the most Chaotic character its wearer knew: the Joker. He had already finished his meal and sat quietly going over the major points he planned to discuss at this hastily-called meeting. Yesterday had been a surreal day, even by his standards, and he wanted to discuss the experience with other acknowledged experts of the surreal.

Harry had briefly considered not inviting Ron to attend this meeting. Ron was the newest member of the Lords of Chaos, having joined only after his marriage to Luna and he began working at WWW with Fred and George and their wives. Harry also knew that Ron had nursed a long-time resentment of him over Hermione; they had briefly dated in their sixth year, when Hermione was experimenting with seeing other people. She and Harry had not resumed their own relationship until after both of them had finished college, in 2003 — the year Harry had started TBC Enterprises and Minister of Magic Rufus Scrimgeour brought her aboard the Ministry in the Department of International Magical Cooperation to run the International Magical Office of Law Department. Ron still had a lingering crush on Hermione, Harry knew. In fact, just about everyone in Ron's family knew it, though none of them would ever tell him so — Ron would likely die of mortification if he ever found out. So, Harry would just grin and bear the resentment. And after all, Ron had turned into a valuable member of Team Weasley — he had come up with several money-spinning items over the past decade, after he'd joined WWW in 2006, two years after he had married Luna Lovegood, and left his job at the Ministry, when Hermione had become Minister of Magic.

At length the last piece of fish had been finished off, the last chip chomped, and the last mug of mead quaffed. Masks were pulled back into place, a wave of a wand Vanished the wrappers and empty mugs from the table, and a deep voice called the meeting to order. "Let's have this meeting come to order, shall we?"

"We shall," the others intoned. "Beginning with the singing of the Song of Chaos!" Everyone cleared their throats, then began:

Chaos Lords, we are Four, yes we are!
Chaos Lords, Evermore, yes we are!
Never will there be any Order in us,
It's only Chaos for us, evermore, evermore!
Ever will we seek Disorder in us,
It's only Chaos for us, this we swore, this we swore!

(sung to the tune of Star Wars' "Imperial March")

The original Song of Chaos had been simpler ("doom" being the only word used in the song), but Fred and George had soon added more lyrics. Adding Ron to the Order had had made their number four, which allowed for a slightly better rhyme (instead of "Chaos Lords, we are Three, yes we be!").

Fred wiped away a nonexistent tear from the side of his mask, its mouth now turned downward in Tragedy. "I really love that song," he said, softly. "It puts me in a very chaotic mood."

"Very appropriate," George agreed. His own mask had a look of Bemused Sadness on it. "Shall we waive the reading of the previous meeting's minutes?"

"Seems like a good idea," Ron noted, wryly. "Since I don't have them anyway."

"Why did you become secretary, then?" Fred remarked, disapprovingly.

"Because you made me," Ron retorted. Fred and George's masks both smiled.

"Ah, knew there was a good reason," George said, as his and his twin's masks now showed Amusement.

"Ahem," Harry said, softly, and three masks turned toward him. "I've called this meeting of the Lords of Chaos to discuss a mystery I discovered yesterday during my interview with James Monroe, the Muggle magazine journalist." He went on to explain about seeing Monroe as a child at Hogwarts, an apparent impossibility as he was a Muggle, and Monroe's inability to explain why he'd been there.

Fred and George's masks were both showing Intense Concentration on them. "That's a poser," Fred finally muttered, his mask changing to Bewildered Confusion. "The most obvious first guess would be a false memory."

"Checked for that," Harry nodded. "If it was a false memory, it was created by a Perfect Occlumens, and this Muggle couldn't be one of those."

Ron spoke from behind his mask. "So maybe some wizard is out to get you, using this Muggle as a cat's-paw."

"That was the obvious second guess," Harry agreed. "But I detected no traces of magic on him at all, except for my own spells." One of the catch-22's of magic use was that no matter how carefully a wizard cleaned up after himself, traces of magic remained on anything it had been cast upon, whether mineral, vegetable, or animal — or Muggle. "If some wizard could remove every trace of his enchantments on Monroe, I'd like to meet him."

"That doesn't leave us many options," Fred's mask showed Intense Concentration once again.

"I know," Harry replied levelly. "I may have to hire the three of you to try and sleuth this out, if we can't come up with a reasonable hypothesis or two to work with during this meeting. If I didn't know better," he continued, smiling behind his Joker mask, "I'd think you did this — it has all the earmarks of the Rita Skeeter scandal you pulled back in 1991, when she was out to get me."

Fred and George's masks glanced toward each other, Wry Embarrassment flashing across them. "Harry," Fred said, looking back at him. "There's something we never told you about that prank…"

=ooo=

"What?" Harry shouted, his Joker face almost mirroring the look of stunned surprise on his hidden face. "You don't know how you did that?"

"It's why we never told you," George admitted, his mask showing Sheepish Chagrin. "We didn't know ourselves."

The first time Harry had learned the details of The Prank of the Century (which is how he had thought of it ever since it happened) was when he purchased a copy of the Daily Prophet during a trip to Diagon Alley with Professor Quirrell to get some Christmas spending money from his vault at Gringotts on the first Sunday of October 1991. The headline had read:

Harry Potter
Secretly Betrothed
to Ginevra Weasley

The evidence provided by the article had been quite compelling. Skeeter had claimed to have seen the original proceedings of the restricted Wizengamot session that heard the details of the contract between one Arthur Weasley (Fred, George and Ron's father) and one James Potter (Harry's father) that included testimony by the Grand Manager of Gringotts, one of the Ministry's Unspeakables, a Bavarian seer, a few centaurs, as well as a prophecy involving, apparently, Harry, Ginny, and He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named, even though no names had been named. Skeeter's article had gone on at length with all the lurid details about Mr. Weasley's desperation and greed, James Potter's cunning and his manipulation of the situation, and the final approval of the goblin Grand Manager, who had affixed the Great Seal of Gringotts to the contract, which demanded the hand in marriage of Ginevra Weasley, recently born at that time, to Harry James Potter, James Potter's son, in payment for the debt Arthur Weasley owed him, a debt incurred when James Potter, an Auror, had killed a Death Eater who had placed Mr. Weasley under the Imperius Curse, thus freeing him. In return, Mr. Weasley had demanded a bride price of ten thousand Galleons.

The only problem with all of this compelling evidence was that it was completely contradicted by the facts. The original proceedings of the Wizengamot contained details on no such betrothal, the dragon-guarded vault supposedly holding the betrothal contract held no such contract, and Arthur Weasley, when questioned by the Ministry, remembered no such contract with James Potter, whom he barely knew, nor even that he had ever been Imperiused. The veracity of the article in shambles, both Skeeter and the editor of the Prophet had disappeared shortly thereafter, presumably shamed beyond all recovery.

Harry had pleaded, begged, had even whined abjectly, trying to get Fred and George to reveal the details of how they had done it, but they had merely grinned evilly and left Harry hanging. Until this very day, he had never known that the twins themselves could never figure how they had done all that with the forty Galleons seed money Harry had given them to publicly humiliate Rita Skeeter at her own game.

In the here and now, he was staring at the twin golden masks in outraged confusion. "It's been twenty-five bloody years! Why didn't you tell me before now?"

George's mask took on the image of Bewildered Innocence. "We just never thought about it after that day you asked us to tell you what we'd done, Harry."

"Never thought about it?" This outburst came, surprisingly, from Ron. "Didn't you know Ginny read that article in the Prophet? Dad brought home a copy of the paper the Monday after it appeared in the paper, to show Mum, and Ginny got ahold of it somehow! She wrote me asking if it was true, was she really betrothed to Harry Potter! I tried telling it couldn't be true, that Dad would never do anything like that, but she wanted me to ask you two!"

"Which you never did," Fred pointed out, laconically, though his mask, and George's, were both showing Mortified Empathy on it for their sister.

"Right, what was I gonna say — 'Hey Fred and George, did Dad really sell Ginny's hand in marriage to Harry Potter's father for ten thousand Galleons?' If he did, he never spent a Knut of that on us!" Ron's Ghostface mask didn't change expression like Fred and George's, but Harry could feel the Outraged Anger radiating from the youngest Weasley brother. "Mum wrote me a few days later, the Aurors came and talked to Dad, and they cleared him of doing anything wrong, but they never told Ginny a thing — figured she was too young to understand…" Ron's mask was shaking back and forth. "But she's always believed that someday Harry would tell her that they were supposed to be together, that he had to — m-marry — Hermione for political reasons…" Ron's mask glanced momentarily toward Harry, who could feel the look of bitter resentment that Ron shot at him behind his mask. "I can't believe you two never figured that out about her."

"Ron, look —" George began, his voice conciliatory. "We'll tell Ginny, we'll make things right with her —"

"Damn straight you will," Ron growled, anger still radiating from him. He folded his arms across his chest and turned away from them, looking as if he would refuse to say anything else during the meeting.

Well, Harry thought. Things certainly weren't going as he'd hoped they would during this meeting. But perhaps that was appropriate for a group that called itself the "Lords of Chaos." Ginny had been nursing a secret crush on him, all these years? It explained a few things about her that Harry noted over the years — the Muggle training she'd taken after retiring from the Holyoke Harpies, all of time she'd spent with him at TBC working late into the evening to finish projects; even her marriage to Dean Thomas, whom she'd dated while at Hogwarts, when Harry brought Dean onboard TBC as his head of security; Dean left the Auror Department at the Ministry to come work for him, for better pay and benefits.

But all of this was still secondary to his primary motivation for calling this meeting: Harry still had to work out how Monroe could have been at Hogwarts in 1991 when he was clearly a Muggle, and had never been seen again at Hogwarts by any of them gathered here. Until he did that, his ultimate goal was in jeopardy.

"We'll set things straight with Ginny," Harry agreed, quietly. "I'll talk to her when I get back —"

Ron laughed, a single harsh, barking sound. "Why bother?" he said bitterly, his mask still turned away from the other three Lords of Chaos. "You've got your perfect little life — why muck with it?"

"Ron!" Fred said sharply. "It's not Harry's fault —"

"Maybe it is," Harry interrupted. "I did ask you and George to take on my Rita Skeeter project. And, however it was accomplished, Ginny and your parents were pulled into it. That makes it my fault." He was looking at Ron as he said it.

"We don't see it that way, Harry," George argued. "You had no idea what we were going to come up with. Neither did we, for that matter." Both Fred and George's masks were showing Sheepish Embarrassment. "The last thing either of us remembers is that old Ambrosius Flume turned down our request for his help in the Skeeter scam. We figured Flume pointed us to someone who could help us, but wanted us Obliviated afterwards so we couldn't implicate him in the scam if we were questioned."

"That's all well and good," Ron said, still looking away from all of them. "But didn't you at least consider what a prank like that was going to do to Ginny, not to mention Dad and Mum?"

"I'm sure they did," Harry answered before either Fred or George could open their mouths. "But, there's something else to consider as well."

Ron's hood turned, bringing part of his Ghostface mask into view. "Like what?" he wanted to know.

"That Fred and George weren't the ones who thought up the Prank — that someone else, someone who didn't bother to consider the consequences to your family, came up with it," Harry said.

Fred and George both blinked at the same moment. "Harry," Fred said gently — it was gallant of Harry to try and exculpate them in Ron's eyes — but still! "Harry, that kind of Prank is right up our alley, chaotically speaking. George and I must have come up with it — we just don't know how we pulled it off on a budget of forty Galleons."

"Unless whoever Obliviated you put the suggestion in your minds that you had come up with the Prank," Harry pointed out. Fred and George's masks frowned with Obstinate Stubbornness at that — it was inconceivable that, after all these years, they might not have come up with the Prank of the Century.

"Who could have done it, then?" Fred wanted to know. "Nobody even questioned us about it, but we were the obvious choices among the student body at Hogwarts, except for, well, you, Harry."

Harry had been questioned by Aurors, under Veritaserum, with Dumbledore present and giving the Aurors scary looks, and had been completely exonerated. "Right," Harry agreed. "Among the students," he added, pointedly.

Fred and George's masks grinned with Skeptical Humor. "You think a teacher had something to do with it?" Fred asked, doubtfully, then looked to George with Stunned Realization on his mask. "Wait a mo'," he said. "There was that thing with Dumbledore in the hallway, afterwards…"

Harry's Joker mask leaned forward intently. "What do you mean? What happened?"

"We were walking down a seventh-floor corridor a day or two later," George explained, "and Dumbledore walked past us. He happened to sneeze just then, and a small package slipped out of one of his pockets without him noticing. Or, we thought so at the time. Fred and I picked up the package and started to call him back, but we noticed a tag on the package that read "to Fred and George" on it. We opened it and found two WardMaster 1000 ward-breaking monocles in it. Real top-of-the-line magic, those WardMasters.

"At the time," George went on. "We just thought Dumbledore was rewarding us for a job well done. It never occurred to either of us until just now that he might've done that to make us think we'd actually come up with the Prank. We never thought that Dumbledore himself might have been behind it!"

"And we never told anyone about those monocles until now," Fred added. "Not even Lee Jordan. If anyone found out we had them, we'd have been in McGonagall's office faster than a Firebolt Mark V, getting a lecture and probably detention for a year, if not outright expulsion."

"You never even told me!" Ron snapped in an outraged tone.

"Just protecting you, little brother," Fred said, smoothly and soothingly.

"And ourselves," George added, his mask displaying a Roguish Grin. "You never could keep a secret, Ron." Ron's robed shoulders gave a small, angry shrug.

"There's another possibility," Harry spoke up once again. "It might've been Quirrell."

The room went completely silent for several seconds. "Quirrell read Skeeter's article in the Prophet right after I did," he said. "And at the time he seemed quite surprised when I told him that someone at Hogwarts had pulled it off."

"You didn't tell him you'd asked us —?" Fred's mask wore a look of Incredulity.

"No," Harry shook his head. "But he guessed it was you two. I thought he'd figured it out on his own. But if anyone other than Dumbledore was capable of pulling off the Prank, it was him."

There was more silence. Even Ron had turned back to face them when Quirrell was mentioned. No one wanted to mention all the trouble the Defense professor had caused for Harry by the end of his first year at Hogwarts. But, it had all been resolved and Harry had come out on top, somewhat surprisingly — Quirrell had been quite good at his job of Defense professor that year, and he had been much more formidable as an adversary than as a teacher and mentor.

"So…" Fred said, after some time had passed. "How do we figure out whether Quirrell has got anything to do with this Monroe journalist?"

"He can't have!" Ron objected. "He's dead!"

Harry nodded slowly. "He should be dead, that's true. But short of coming up with the Resurrection Stone, assuming it does what the stories say it does, we have no way of testing that idea."

Everyone fell quiet after that, trying to see some way that Quirrell could still be alive. But none of them, save for Harry, knew the truth behind Quirinus Quirrell and why he'd come to Hogwarts in the fall of 1991. That was a secret he intended never to divulge to another person, living or dead.

=ooo=

"How much longer are they going to be?" A harried Verity asked during a rare lull in the rush of customers that bustled through their shop during the course of a normal business day. She glanced upward, as if she could see through the ceiling of Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes into the room where they were gathered with Harry Potter-Evans-Verres, probably discussing their glory days at Hogwarts.

"They haven't had a meeting with Harry in years now," Angelina reminded her. "Probably a lot of catching-up to do."

"They can have business lunches after work, you know," Verity complained, watching potential customers looking through the front windows of their shop. "They're called business dinners."

From behind the counter Luna, who had just finished ringing up a customer's purchases, smiled dreamily and mused, "I think it's interesting when the men aren't on the floor — we seem to sell so much more when they're away, don't you think?"

"Is that how it seems?" Angelina asked, amused. "I always thought we just do a better job of selling than they do — especially Ron."

"Ron would have made a better Auror than a salesman," Luna replied. "But he didn't think he could get the five N.E.W.T.S. he needed to join the program. Novelty salesman was a good second choice for him, I suppose."

"Would you still be working with your father on the Quibbler if you hadn't married Ron?" Verity asked Luna, then walked off to help a customer who was looking around for some help.

"I still do help Father," Luna answered, not realizing Verity was gone. "Especially when he needs a particularly insightful headline. I gave him that one for last month's issue." She pulled a copy of the issue out from under the counter, showing the headline emblazoned across the top of the front page:

Head Auror Malfoy
Secretly Betrothed to
Minerva McGonagall's Ghost.

Angelina smiled. "One of the classics," she said, nodding appreciatively. "Right up there with the Harry secretly betrothed to you, Luna."

Luna turned protuberant eyes on George's wife. "He was secretly betrothed to me, but he and Father worked out an agreement. It's very hush-hush, I'm not even supposed to think about it, much less talk about it."

"I guess we'd better forget you even mentioned it, then," Angelina grinned.

"You should," Luna said, seriously. "I'll have to remember to forget about it as well."

Angelina nodded, turning to hide her amusement from Luna, who was very sweet and a wonderful person, even if she was barmy as a bagful of ferrets.

The shop was beginning to slow down some, now that lunch was over for everyone (almost everyone, Angelina reminded herself, thinking of Verity's annoyance with their husbands' very long lunch with Harry Potter). But if Harry Potter-Evans-Verres could spare an hour and a half for lunch with old friends, who were they to argue with him, and them? Being "in business" with Harry had never been anything but good for Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes; they received rental discounts and perks at Gringotts that no other business had, and as far as Angelina could tell, rental space here in Diagon Alley hadn't changed in years, for anyone.

It would be interesting to hear the conversation that had been going on upstairs for the past ninety minutes, Angelina reflected. Harry Potter-Evans-Verres was a very interesting wizard; he'd left Hogwarts with six N.E.W.T.S., a tie with Albus Dumbledore back in 1899. And then he'd gone on to college at Oxford, graduating with two degrees in three-and-a-half years. Within a year after graduating from that prestigious Muggle institution, he had started a corporation and built it into a global power. Somewhere in there he'd found the time to take over Gringotts from the goblins and buy up most of the property in Diagon Alley. If Angelina had known the Ravenclaw a little better she might have taken a run at him herself.

But she and George had grown close over their years at Hogwarts, and he was certainly more approachable than Harry had been, back then, even after he and Fred started WWW. She might have married Harry Potter for happiness (and money, lots and lots of money), but she married George for love. She could only hope Fred and Verity had married for the same reason.

Ron and Luna were a different matter. Angelina was virtually certain that Ron had "settled" for Luna, even though she was equally certain that they loved one another. It was pretty obvious to anyone who saw Ron on a regular basis, though, that his soulmate was someone else — someone that was now married to Harry Potter. The question was — had Luna figured it out by now? Angelina certainly hoped not, though she couldn't see how Luna could have missed it.

But then, Luna was bat-dung crazy.

Angelina's thoughts were interrupted by a customer who had wandered close to where she was standing. The man was looking around as if he'd never seen a place like WWW before — evidently he was a first-time customer.

"May I help you find something, sir?" she asked, walking toward him. The man started slightly, surprised that she'd spoken to him, then scratched his head sheepishly.

"I'm just looking," he said, perhaps a bit too quickly to be completely true. He was staring at her, looking for all the world like he wanted to ask another question but wasn't sure he should. Finally, he seemed to come to a decision.

"I — ah, thought I might find Harry Potter here," he said, hesitantly.

Angelina blinked. "As a matter of fact, he is," she replied. "But he's in a meeting at the moment. It shouldn't last much longer —" she hoped, it had been going on for over 90 minutes by now! "— if you'd care to wait for him to come down."

"Thank you," the man said, then looked around the store again. "All of this looks very fascinating. Are you one of the Weasleys?"

"I'm married to George Weasley," she told him. "He's one of the owners of the shop. Is there anything you'd like to look at while you're waiting for Mr. Potter?"

The man looked around for a second, then seemed to select one of the items off the shelf at random. "What's this do?"

"A Shield Hat," Angelina nodded, taking it from him. "When you put it on it activates an invisible Shield Charm — you can challenge your friends to try and jinx or hex you, and the shield will protect you from most minor spells. Guaranteed for at least one hundred Shields or your money back."

The man took the hat and was nodding as if he understood, but there was a look in his eyes that made Angelina think he was hiding something. She took the hat from him and casually placed it back on the shelf. "If you're not interested in that," she said, leading him to another shelf, "we have a variety of novelty wands that will do anything from turning into a rubber chicken when waved to leaping out of the wielder's hand and beating him about the head and shoulders."

"Do you have any real wands?" the man asked.

Angelina gave him an odd look. "You can buy real wands at Ollivanders, a few doors down. Mr. Ollivander has passed on, of course, but it's being run now by another one of the Weasley brothers, Bill, for ten years now. Bill took over the business when Mr. Ollivander died in 2006."

"Can a non-magical person use a wand?" the man asked.

Another odd question! "Of course not," Angelina said, frowning. "Only wizards can use wands. Why would you even ask that?"

"Sorry," the man muttered, looking away from her and toward the stairs near the back of the shop. "I — guess I just wasn't thinking. I'll just wait for Mr. Potter."

But by now Angelina had gotten suspicious. "What's your business with Mr. Potter, if I may ask?"

"I just have to talk to him," the man said, evasively. "We have some unfinished business to attend to."

"You might have gone to his business address for that," Angelina said, evenly. "Yet you chose to come here. Why?"

The man was silent for some time before finally shaking his head. "I thought it would be better to meet him here than at his business office. Things didn't work out very well the last time I met him there."

"What happened?" Angelina asked. How did this man know Harry Potter? He didn't seem like any wizard she'd ever met before, but Muggles couldn't get into Diagon Alley without someone with a wand helping them.

The man put on a wry expression. "I don't think he ever expected to see me again," he said, flatly. "But here I am, like the cat that came back the very next day."

Angelina shook her head. "I don't think that's a good idea, sir. Harry Potter is not someone you should be messing with, no matter who you are. You haven't told me your name yet, by the way."

"My name?" the man replied. "I'm James Monroe."

Chapter 19: A Conversation with the Founders

Updated 8/24/2012

=ooo=

"Satisfied?" Harry asked, keeping his voice neutral. He didn't want Malfoy sensing the irritation and anger he was feeling.

"We didn't find anything," Malfoy replied, his tone as neutral as Harry's. "This time," he added. He was far from done with Potter and his sneaking around over the past few months.

It was late in the evening, and the Auror teams that had searched Harry's offices and labs in the TBC Building ("ransacked" had been the term Harry used) had packed up and left, leaving only the Head Auror and his two subordinates, Crabbe and Goyle.

"This time," Harry repeated, softly. He gave Malfoy a condescending look. "You know there's nothing here to find."

"Right," Malfoy agreed, sarcastically. "That's why you showed up as soon as you could after we executed our warrants and stayed here the entire tire, because there's 'nothing here to find.'"

"I just don't want you or your men pulling a fast one," Harry replied. "Look what you did to James Monroe a few months ago — you put an illegal trace spell on him."

"That spell is not illegal," Malfoy snapped.

"But you didn't have clearance to use it," Harry snapped right back.

"There is some discretion over its use by Auror personnel," Malfoy insisted.

Harry smiled. "Apparently not enough in that case," he reminded the Head Auror. "Since you had to remove it on orders from the Minister."

"Your wife," Malfoy sneered, because he had nowhere else to go with it. "Someday she isn't going to be Minister anymore, and who's going to protect you then?"

"I guess we'll just have to wait and see," Harry said, coldly. Malfoy was really beginning to get on his nerves. "Isn't it time you toddled off to bed, to count your failures for the week?"

Malfoy laughed and turned away, seething inwardly. Damn Potter! He might have won this round, but eventually he'd find something that would stick to the man. Motioning for Crabbe and Goyle to step closer, he brought out a parchment envelope that had been enchanted for their return to the Ministry. Crabbe and Goyle each grasped a corner, and Malfoy said, "Activate." The three of them disappeared in a whirlwind of color and light and a pop of air rushing in to fill the space they had occupied.

"Finally," Harry muttered. The only people left in the office now were him and Dean, and Dean was still checking the labs where Aurors had opened every drawer and cupboard, and poked around in every box. He took out his phone and called Dean. "How's it going?" he asked when Dean answered.

"I'm getting things situated again," Dean said, in a tone that suggested he was highly aggravated at Malfoy and his Auror-goons. "They left things a mess, as usual, to show that they can do whatever they want when they have a warrant to back them up."

"Can we finish things up tomorrow?" Harry asked. "I still have stuff to do and there's not that much time left in the day."

"There's no time left in the day," Dean laughed. "It's nearly tomorrow, aleady! But sure, this stuff can wait 'til then." He paused for a moment. "Is Ginny still here?"

"Oh, I sent her home hours ago," Harry replied. "She said she had stuff to do before you got home."

"Oh." Dean couldn't imagine what stuff she meant, but he wasn't altogether sure about a lot of what Ginny did lately. "Okay, well, I'll be there in a minute and we can get out of here."

"Great," Harry said, ending the call. He pocketed his phone and walked over to stand next to the elevator. His next stop was back to Hogwarts to see what Monroe had found out in the Room of Requirement. He just hoped James hadn't been stuck outside the Room this whole time, as funny (in a way) as that would be. Some people just couldn't do what it took to get into the Room of Requirement. James was a pretty intelligent guy, but that by itself was no guarantee of success. When Harry got there, he would find out soon enough which side of the door Monroe was on.

=ooo=

At the Ministry, the Auror teams that had just left the TBC building were busy writing the reports that would go to the Head Auror, then to the Minister herself. At least, that was how things were supposed to work.

Given the amount of time the Auror Department had spending analyzing information related to TBC and Harry Potter over the past few weeks, some Aurors privately wondered just how much the Head Auror actually told the Minister what was going on with her husband, given the setbacks the Head had suffered in the past few months. But theirs was not to wonder why, theirs was but to do and report on it. Carefully. Especially so with Lord Malfoy's son as their boss.

Malfoy himself was in his office, going over the last bits of incoming correspondence before leaving until Monday morning. There were several status reports from the end of the week; he set those aside for next week. Manpower reports, also into the pile for next week. A couple of owl posts… he would read those then call it a day. His wife was probably wondering what was keeping him. He should have owled her, probably, but she was used to him by now, he hoped.

The first owl was from one of the shopkeepers in Diagon Alley protesting the recent rental hike on his shop. And apparently he didn't buy the Ministry's official explanation that Harry Potter had requested the hike. He had written that according to the Quibbler, blah, blah blah.

Draco mentally shrugged. Where old Xenophilius Lovegood pulled those stories of his from would probably make an interesting story in itself. Never mind that in this case he happened to be right, for once — Potter had little to do with how the rental rates were determined in Diagon Alley, other than the fact that he had hooks into most of the businesses there and that was why Draco kept getting the rates bumped up every so often. That owl would go into his "special" file on Potter.

The next owl he stared at for some time, recognizing the writing on the envelope. It was in the distinctive script of a Weasley Anony-Quill.

He ran his finger along the edge of the envelope, wandlessly casting Diffindo, and the letter slid into his hand. As he expected it was once again about Potter; this time the writer was saying that Potter had been to the Chamber of Secrets at Hogwarts, that he had found out something about the statue of Salazar Slytherin there. What, specifically he'd found out, the letter didn't say, but letter went on to urge him to stop Potter from undermining the rule of the Ministry and the Wizengamot. What, Draco wondered, could Potter have discovered that would undermine either of those? That would be nearly impossible, even considering that one of his friends was now the Chief Wizard of the Wizengamot.

Unless he'd found some way to make either the Ministry or the Wizengamot, or both, powerless to stop him, somehow. Potter and his minion Monroe had been poking around in exotic ideas lately, things like where the source of magic came from, whether magic could somehow be made to increase without limit, or if he'd found some way around the Interdict of Merlin. None of those scenarios boded well for the future of the Ministry, or for Draco's future, if he wasn't positioned properly when Potter made his play.

Draco dropped the letter on his desk, then closed his eyes and tried to think. This was the third letter he'd received from his "confidential informant" about Potter and his activities, and the evidence pointed to a Weasley — ostensibly Ron since he knew the second-youngest Weasley sibling didn't care too much for Potter, not like the rest of his family, who practically idolized him.

But Ron Weasley wasn't the sort of fellow who could get the kind of information the letters Draco had on his own. He was no dummy, of course; like his brothers, their Hogwarts transcripts didn't give a good indication of how smart they really were. Between Fred and George together they'd earned only three O.W.L.s, and Ron had earned only six, most of those with help from the other Gryffindors (and probably Granger as well, they were more-or-less friendly during their fifth year, Draco remembered). Yet the three of them and their spouses were running two very successful shops in Diagon Alley, shops that sold some pretty sophisticated magic items, if you ignored the fact they were mostly mimicking Muggle technology or were novelty and joke items. Even the Auror Department used Weasley technology — on the Q.T. of course; Draco didn't want them knowing their devices were in his offices, even though those devices had been checked for hidden spells and such.

Still, Ron Weasley probably wasn't the instigator of these letters, not on his own. At least that was Draco's working hypothesis — he could be wrong, but if so that would make things simpler, not harder.

And from there it was easy enough to decide what to do. Draco grabbed a quill and parchment and wrote down his plan, then left his office, stopping at Mr. Crabbe's cubicle. "New plan," he told Vincent, dropping the parchment on his desk.

Vincent Crabbe glanced up at his boss, a neutral expression on his face, then picked up the parchment and began to read. He blinked a couple of times, but kept himself from blanching. "You mean now?" he finally asked, trying to keep the aggravation out of his voice. Nobody in the department was going to be happy about this.

"Now," Draco affirmed. "I want to catch them off-guard. Each team should have enough Veritaserum for three people, in case the interrogations go long or someone else becomes available. Make sure to check each person for the antidote. And make sure no one is able to communicate with anyone else — I don't want to give them any chance of cooking up a story for us. Get it done. I'll be here if you need me."

Crabbe nodded, then went to let Goyle in on their new task. Draco went back to his office, hoping that nothing went wrong with this plan. He needed to find out once and for all who was feeding him information about Potter, and why.

=ooo=

Harry Apparated just outside Hogsmeade, this time beneath his Cloak of Invisibility. He paused for a moment, considering his options. It was going to be more difficult to get into Hogwarts than it had been getting out of it. Difficult, but certainly not impossible. Under the Cloak, with a Silencing Charm in place to keep his footsteps and breathing from being heard, the only thing that could locate him under his Cloak was something he already had with him — the Marauder's Map.

Harry made his way down the road leading to the gates of the castle wall, using moonlight to guide him. The gates were his first problem. It was past midnight and they would certainly be locked. He pondered for a moment, then decided to see if his trick door would work. He pulled it out of the mokeskin pouch but the cylinder wouldn't pass between the bars of the gate. So much for that. He tried the walls on either side of the gate, with the same luck.

Good for Neville, he and his staff were keeping up with the times, Harry smiled to himself. He tried several unlocking spells on the lock and chains holding the gate closed, with no success. He had a potion of spider-climbing in his pouch but certainly the wall would be warded for things like that. It was tempting to give it a try, though, just in case Neville and his staff had overlooked it.

But, no. And while there were several other items in his pouch that he might have used in various novel ways to defeat the gate, there was an alternate solution that would probably work just as well, though it would call attention to him. Harry reached into his pouch and pulled out his broomstick. Mounting it still covered in his Cloak, Harry pushed off, his wand in his hand, and flew upward and into a loop that took him directly over the wall.

As he passed over the wall the wards immediately kicked in, neutralizing his broom's flying ability. Harry glided gently to the ground. He'd known that the wards would not simply drop him (or anyone) to the ground. He quickly stuffed the broom back in his pouch then cast a Silencing Charm on the inside of the Cloak and hurried toward the front doors. If he was fast enough he'd get there before anyone came out to investigate.

He stopped at the base of the front stairs. Someone from the staff, possibly Neville himself, would be checking to see who'd set off the anti-flight wards on the castle perimeter. They would be casting detection spells to check for the presence of intruders. So — Harry would have to make himself scarce for a few minutes. That's where his pouch would once again come in handy.

Neville Longbottom, Headmaster of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, strode down the grand staircase into the Entrance Hall of the school, his now slightly lined face frowning with apprehension. Who could have set off the flight wards at this time of night? Had some student been out having a midnight flight at the Quidditch pitch and flew out of bounds? Or was something more serious going on? He paused at the double oaken doors, still bolted and locked, and cast the spells to unlock them. He then sent a Homenum Revelio spell through the door, to check for any humans outside. None were detected within range of the spell.

Two fifth-year Hufflepuff prefects rushed into the Entrance Hall through the door leading to their common room. "We just heard the alarm, Headmaster!" the girl, Eileen Weatherly, said breathlessly. "Do you need any help?"

"I don't think so, Eileen," Neville replied, smiling at her and James Brandson, her fellow prefect. "But why don't you two wait here until I return, keep things safe and tell any of the other prefects or teachers that show up that I'm having a look round outside."

The two prefects nodded, and Neville waved his wand again. One of the oaken doors slowly opened, and he stepped through. The door began to slowly close again, then wobbled for a moment before it finally shut.

"That was weird," James said, walking over to stare at the big oaken door. "I wonder what's wrong with this thing? I never saw it do that before."

"The Headmaster was probably distracted," Eileen guessed. James shrugged, then stood a bit straighter. He'd been charged with securing this room, and he intended to do just that.

Under his Cloak, Harry paused on the staircase landing and smiled at the two students. It was hard to remember when he was that young. The entrance door had almost closed on him as he slipped past Neville; he'd had to step lively to get through, and the door had brushed against him anyway.

Harry had waited at the top of the stairs, hidden inside his pouch, until his detection spells told him a Human Revealment Charm had been cast. He and Quirrell had once used his original pouch to hide the Defense professor, in his Animagus snake-form, inside it. With this improved version, Harry could put much larger objects inside, including himself, using a special keyword when he put his hand in the pouch's mouth. Another keyword would reverse that.

The door had opened just as he stood and Neville stepped outside, allowing Harry entry. He moved away from the two students who were staring curiously at the door, and made his way up the staircase to the first floor. Only six more to go before he got to the seventh floor and the Room of Requirement.

=ooo=

Fred Weasley snuggled against his wife's sleeping form, enjoying the warmth her body created. It had been a long day in the shop, with too much of it taken up explaining to a potential customer how a Weasley-modified iPhone (the Weasley wPhone 5) was many times superior to owl posts — with their new Owl Post Service you could send a message to a wizard who did not possess a wPhone of their own: Weasleys' Wireless Wonderland had an agreement with the Diagon Alley Owlery, in which they'd installed a device to transcribe messages onto parchment, attach it to an owl, and send it off to the intended witch or wizard.

Fred was proud of that device, and rightly so — it had taken some time before the owls understood who they were supposed to take the message to, even when the device spoke the name clearly and distinctly. The old wizard who ran the Owlery was even harder to convince; he'd scratched the wart on his chin, frowning, and said he'd never heard of such a thing as a box telling his owls where to go! Only a wizard could do that! Fred had to cut the man in on 10 percent of the profits before he'd agree to try it. But it was working smooth as glass now, and Weasley wPhones accounted for 27 percent of all the messages sent from the Owlery these days. The old man was usually smiling whenever Fred saw him these days; he'd even added a couple of long-distance owls to his business since partnering with the Weasleys.

By contrast, though, what Fred really wanted to spend more time doing was research on new ideas for their wireless and electronics business. There were several concents in the Muggle marketplace of ideas that could be adapted for the Wizarding community. One was a GPS system for brooms. GPS stood for "global positioning system," a means of knowing where you were and for directing you to your desired location, and while you could use Muggle GPS systems on a broom now, they had to be carefully protected from magic or they tended not to work right. Fred wanted to develop a magical GPS, one that could be affixed to any broom to allow the rider to simply follow its directions without continual course correction and needless detours, something that was difficult to get Muggle GPSs to do unless you were flying at almost street level, which wasn't practical unless the broom had an Invisibility Booster, and then it was still dangerous in areas with tall vehicles like trucks and double-decker buses. A magical GPS would be something like the Marauder's Map, but with a much wider mapping area, and it had to be done on the fly. He might have to borrow the Map back from Harry, so he could do some reverse-engineering on it.

Even bolder was his idea to develop a self-flying broom, a broom that you could just get on and tell it, for example, "Take me to Aunt Muriel's house," and it would take off and fly you there without you having to control the broom at all. That was slower going; Fred was having to bone up on fleobromolgy, the study of magical flying brooms — flying charms, braking charms, the charms used to control the steering of the broom; it turned out enchanting a single broom was a very complex procedure, especially if you wanted Firebolt-quality performance, and Fred would accept nothing less from any brooms his shops produced.

Verity stirred beside him, and Fred waited to see if she was going to wake up. It would be nice if she did — she usually woke up feeling amorous, and Fred wouldn't mind if they decided to spend a few intimate moments before falling back to sleep. But Verity only rolled onto her side, facing away from him, her breathing still low and steady.

Oh well, Fred thought to himself, there's always time for a little bit before we get up in the morning, and rolled onto his side as well. Verity could be quite randy some mornings —

Wham. Fred winced as if he'd been struck. Had Verity just hit him? He looked back at her — no, she hadn't moved! What was going on —? Then he realized what he'd felt.

Fred slipped out of bed, grabbing his housecoat and slipping it on in one fluid motion as he moved toward the door of their bedroom. What he'd felt was the wards protecting the shop downstairs catastrophically collapsing. Someone (likely more than a single wizard) had cast a powerful ward-breaking curse. They were under attack.

George's door opened as Fred approached it and his twin brother joined him as they rushed towards the staircase. "How many, d'you think?" George asked.

Another door opened behind him and the twins knew that Ron was with them. "What the hell was that?" Ron was saying.

"Has to be at least a half-dozen," Fred answered George as they started down the stairs. "Protection wards breaking," he threw over his shoulder to their youngest brother. "Be ready for anything," he added, unnecessarily.

"Don't move!" voices suddenly shouted at them from the bottom of the staircase. The light of multiple Lumos charms glared at them.

Both Fred and George's wands were pointing toward the lights. "Who's there?!" Fred called out. "Who are you?!"

"Ministry Aurors! Drop your wands and come down slowly!' a voice replied.

As one, the twins filled the space in front of them with Shield Charms. "I think we'll make sure who you are, first," Fred drawled. "What are you doing here in the middle of the night on a weekend? Pubs close early?"

"We're here to question you," the voice said, sounding very annoyed at being questioned himself under these circumstances.

"About…?" Fred prompted, with false politeness.

"We'll discuss that with each of you during questioning," the voice snapped.

"Each of us?" George didn't like the sound of that. "Who d'you intend to question?"

"I have orders to question all of you," the Auror behind the lights growled angrily. "Each of you, and each of your wives. You are doing yourselves no favors by not cooperating!"

Fred and George glanced at one another, each with the same thought — this was about Harry. It had to be. They both glanced back at Ron.

"What?" Ron whispered apprehensively. "I didn't do anything!"

"You better not have," Fred whispered back, threateningly. "They're going to question all of us, probably separately and probably about Harry."

"Oh," Ron said, looking even more apprehensive now. "Er —"

"Oh, bollocks, " George snapped. He cast a Silencing Charm around the three of them before asking, "You did do something, didn't you?!"

"What was it?" Fred demanded.

Ron sighed. "I sent a few letters to Malfoy."

"About what?"

"Saying that he should, um, investigate Harry a bit more closely. But I used an Anony-Quill!"

"Oh, Merlin's pants," Fred groaned. "He probably traced it to us."

"Lower your wands!" the Auror said again, more insistently. "You have three seconds —"

"We have to figure out what to tell these guys," Fred began, but —

"That's it! Take 'em!" the Auror shouted, and several Stunners bounced off their Shields. "Again!" More bangs and red flashes as Stunners expended themselves."

"Hold 'em," Fred muttered to George, then suddenly turned his wand back on Ron. Before Ron could react Fred said softly, "Obliviate!" and Ron suddenly got a faraway look in his eyes, like he had just awakened.

"Hope I got everything," Fred whispered to George, then canceled the Silencing Charm and shouted, "Oi! All right, we give up, we're lowering our wands!"

The twins offered no resistance as Disarming Charms relieved them of their wands and Aurors stormed up the stairs, grabbing each of them in turn and hustling them down into the shop. More Aurors ran upstairs. Fred smiled slightly as they tripped the intruder spells set for anyone other than friends and family of the Weasleys. There were going to be some rather disconcerted Aurors getting anatomy-switching hexes removed before any of them were questioned. Which, he added glumly to himself, wasn't going to make up for the yelling-at he was going to get from his wife when she was awakened by an Auror with his arse where his face ought to be.

=ooo=

Hogwarts was a rather busy place late at night, even on weekends, Harry reflected, having passed a few more pairs of prefects patrolling corridors, more than a few pairs of students snogging in corners, and one rather inquisitive Kneazle that seemed to stare at him right through his Cloak for quite a while before going its own way.

He'd also caught a glimpse of Nearly Headless Nick on the fifth floor as the Gryffindor house ghost floated out of one wall, across the corridor in front of him, and into another. Ghosts were another aspect of the whole "soul" thing he and Monroe had been debating the past few months; it was difficult to come across even one in most British towns, even those with a wizarding population, but Hogwarts had something like two dozen of them: four official House ghosts: Nearly Headless Nick, the Bloody Baron, the Fat Friar and the Gray Lady, along with Myrtle and Professor Binns, to name but a few. If they were merely afterimages impressed upon this world because of an unexpected or violent death, rather than actual souls, what would it take to dissipate them, and should anyone do so, unless there really was an afterlife waiting for them? Those were the kinds of questions he and James had been going back and forth with.

Once on the seventh floor, Harry stopped at a quiet corner and brought out the thing he'd been anxious to try again since returning to Hogwarts — the Marauder's Map. He pulled the large blank piece of parchment out of his pouch and tapped it with his wand, murmuring, "I solemnly swear that I am up to no good."

Lines began flowing across the blank parchment, creating a map of the castle complete with labeled dots indicating the person they represented. When Fred and George had given him this, they said they believed it was part of the original Hogwarts security system. What they didn't know was that Harry knew that Remus Lupin, who had taught Defense for a year at Hogwarts, was the Moony named as one of its authors, along with Prongs, Padfoot and Wormtail, who were in reality Harry's father James, his best friend Sirius Black, and Peter Pettigrew. An unlikely quartet, Harry had thought at the time. Far from being nearly 800 years old, the Marauer's Map had only been around since the mid 1970's, when Lupin, Black, Pettigrew and his father had been in their upper years at the school. Lupin had promised to tell him sometime how they'd created it, but he'd never gotten around to it, and he was too busy these days for Harry to bother him over it. But he really should — the Map was extraordinary magic, and Harry was very interested in how students who weren't even fully-qualified wizards had managed to create it.

But on to his primary use for the Map right now, which was to find out how many students or staff members were near the corridor where the Room of Requirement was located, and to check whether James Monroe had made it into the Room or not. At the moment, Harry saw, no one was in the corridor in question, not even Monroe, which was a good thing. Still carrying the Map, and crouching slightly to keep his feet hidden, Harry made his way to the corridor.

"Mischief managed." He folded the still-disappearing Map and slipped it back into his pouch, then took off the Cloak and did the same with it, and stood regarding the blank wall where the door to the Room of Requirement would appear. Assuming Monroe was in there, Harry had to send him a signal that would unambiguously identify him. That would be easy enough to do.

Harry placed the tip of his wand against the wall, activated a spell, then said, "Recognition code 927, I am a potato." The spell would project his words through the wall to the other side.

It was nearly a minute, however, before a door formed on Harry's side of the wall and cracked open a bit. A pair of eyes stared out at Harry, and the door opened wide, revealing a tired-looking James Monroe. "That had to be you," he grinned at Harry.

"What have you found out —" Harry began, moving to come inside, but Monroe put out a hand, stopping him, then stepped outside.

"Don't let the door go shut!" Harry said quickly, and Monroe nodded, took out his wand and conjured a brick in his other hand. He placed the brick in the doorway so the door would remain open.

"Before you go in there," he prefaced, "I need to let you in on what I've found. Apparently the four Founders transferred a part of themselves into the castle itself. Like a Horcrux, but also not like one."

Harry was intrigued. This was just the break they'd been hoping for! In fact it wildly exceeded their expectations! "How so?" he asked excitedly.

"Whatever they did, it didn't require murder to complete the ritual," Monroe explained. "I don't know if the statue of Slytherin in the Chamber is a Horcrux or not, I haven't had time to go back and check."

"You've been here something like ten hours now," Harry reminded him.

Monroe nodded excitedly. "Right, I've been busy learning spells from the Founders! The Room's full of old book with Interdict-encrypted spells in them. When I show them a spell I can't read, they can, once they read it to me, I can understand it!"

"So that's it!" Harry all but shouted. "We can beat the Interdict!"

"Yeah," Monroe agreed, then began to sit down. A chair appeared beneath him, and he leaned forward wearily.

"Are you okay?" a suddenly-worried Harry asked him.

"Tired," Monroe muttered. "I've been afraid to stop talking to them or leave the Room — I wasn't sure I could get back in if I left."

"How did you find a room with the Four Founders in it?" Harry wanted to know.

"Not sure. I wanted to find out what you and Slytherin's statue talked about down in the Chamber," Monroe replied, tiredly rubbing his eyes. "Apparently only the Four Founders could answer that question. I don't know. I've wondered why nobody else has come across them before."

"Maybe someone has," Harry speculated. He could imagine one other person who might've had the wherewithal to find and talk to the Four Founders.

"Who?" Monroe asked, then realized who Harry was thinking of. "Oh, you mean Voldemort."

"Yes." Harry's voice was grim. "If that happened, I'm not sure why he's not ruling Britain — or the world — right now."

"Then maybe he didn't," Monroe suggested. "I mean — if you think he destroyed the Basilisk after taking Slytherin's Interdict-level spells from it, why wouldn't he have destroyed the Founders' statues?"

"Why don't we go ask them?" Harry said.

=ooo=

Ginny, dressed in only her nightgown and robe, had been led into the kitchen of her and Dean's apartment and seated in a kitchen chair. The table had been Vanished and the two Aurors sat facing her in the other chairs. Dean was presumably in the other room with two different Aurors, undergoing the same procedure.

She had been advised of her rights (which at the moment weren't very useful, since she was not yet charged with anything) and asked if she would submit to interrogation under Veritaserum. The alternative, the two Aurors told her, would mean being charged with obstruction of justice (a term borrowed from Muggle legalese meaning, she wasn't being completely cooperative) and a full-scale investigation into her activities would be conducted while she was detained in Azkaban. A very unpleasant alterative, to be sure.

Ginny had nodded agreement, not speaking, and the senior Auror told her to answer verbally. "I agree," she said, adding, "Pursuant to Section Two of the Unified Wizards' Code of 2012, paragraph 14."

The senior Auror smiled mirthlessly. "I see you know your rights, Mrs. Thomas," he said, his voice low and rumbling. He was a large man, with perhaps a bit of giant blood in him, as his head reached nearly to the ceiling of the room when he stood up; he'd had to stoop to walk through doorways. "I wonder why you feel the need to invoke that particular right."

"Somehow I don't see you reminding me of its existence," Ginny replied, curtly. The law she'd quoted guaranteed that if no charges were filed as a result of her interrogation, any transcripts or Pensieve memories generated from her questioning would be destroyed. The only place interrogation could exist was in the minds of the individuals who were directly involved in it.

"Very well," the big Auror said. "Give it to her," he said to the other Auror, a younger man only a few years out of Auror Training. The younger Auror handed Ginny a glass of water containing three drops of Veritaserum.

Ginny took the glass and calmly drank it, passing the empty glass back to the Aurors. "Go ahead," she said. "Ask your questions."

"In a minute," the big Auror said. "Give it a while to take effect."

Ginny sat impassively, looking at the two men in turn: the big Auror made the chair he was sitting in look like a child's chair, and the younger Auror who kept stealing glances at his senior counterpart. "I would like to get some sleep tonight," she said at last.

"I'm sure you would," the big Auror drawled. He smiled a crooked smile. "But we have miles to go before you sleep, Mrs. Thomas. Miles to go before you sleep."

Chapter 21: The Ginny Factor

Updated 9/29/2012

"Okay, so what do we do now?" Monroe wanted to know.

Harry shrugged. "I don't know if we need to do anything," he replied, casually. "You can't get into the Room of Requirement unless you know exactly what someone who's already inside needed. I would defy anyone to guess that we've summoned the essences of the four Founders to teach us pre-Interdict spell magic."

Monroe nodded ruefully; Harry had a point. "But that means we're stuck in here until they go away," he also pointed out. "All Malfoy has to do is rotate his Aurors to guard the entrance until we have to leave."

"Why would we have to leave?" Harry asked, in a bland tone.

"Well, because —" Monroe stopped and smiled. "You're right, we don't." The pre-Interdict spells and rituals they'd learned would allow them to stay here almost indefinitely. They could summon food, water, and most importantly, more books with pre-Interdict spells in them, and have the Founders read them to Harry and him. And now, with their newly-Memory Enhanced minds, they would remember every single spell, ritual, and potion recipe they learned. "So what do we do next?" he asked.

Harry thought for a while. "I don't know at the moment," he finally said. "Let me think about it a bit."

=ooo=

Revealment spells cast toward the wall where the Room of Requirement was supposed to appear showed nothing and no one beyond it, even though this was the last known location of James Monroe.

"Is there any way we can find out who's in there?" Malfoy asked Neville.

"Other than having them tell us, or figuring out exactly what they're using the room for, I doubt it," Neville replied.

"We could break through," Crabbe suggested.

Both Neville and Malfoy shook their heads. "I can't authorize that," Draco said.

"And I wouldn't allow it," Neville said, in a stern voice. Malfoy gave him an amused look but didn't argue the point. He turned to the other Aurors. "Suggestions, gentlemen?"

The Aurors shook their heads. "Headmaster?" Malfoy turned to Neville once again. "Anything you can think of? What about that magical security system, can it tell us who's inside?"

"No, I've already told you so," Neville answered, annoyed. "It can tell us everyone who's on school grounds, but the Weasleys could never make it work for the Room of Requirement. It can't see inside there at all."

Draco could see a way around that limitation, however. "It can tell us everyone who's entered Hogwarts but hasn't left," he pointed out.

Neville blinked. "Of course," he nodded. "Security," he said. "Tell us everyone who has entered Hogwarts and has not left yet."

"Vincent Crabbe," the cool voice recited. "Gregory Goyle, Draco Malfoy, James Monroe, Harry Potter —"

"Stop!" Draco called out, and Neville echoed the order, stopping the recitation. "That's interesting," he smirked. "Potter came back, apparently. Find out when he returned," he told Neville, who repeated the question.

"Harry Potter entered Hogwarts at twelve-fifteen a.m. this morning," the Security voice replied.

"Why didn't you tell me he'd returned when I asked you earlier?" Neville demanded.

"Your question about Harry Potter's arrivals and departures from Hogwarts referred to yesterday, not today," the cool voice replied. Neville snorted annoyance, shaking his head.

"So Potter and Monroe are in there," Malfoy pondered, staring at the blank wall. "But we can't make them come out and we can't get inside unless we know what they're using the Room for. That's a pretty problem."

"Sure we can't just bust in?" Crabbe muttered.

"No," Neville said. "You're not destroying the Room of Requirement —"

"Not if we can help it," Malfoy finished. "But if they're doing something in there that might compromise the Interdict of Merlin —"

"And what do you think something like that would take?" Neville interrupted in turn. "Wizards have been studying the Interdict for 800 years now; its scope has expanded from Britain to nearly the entire world — only the most remote, inaccessible reaches of the earth have not been touched by it. Since it has a limiting effect on the ability to communicate magical knowledge except from one mind to another, it is likely to remain in place forever."

"You don't know that," Malfoy objected.

"You're the one that was with Harry when he figured all that out, back in our first year!" Neville countered. "Magical knowledge is being limited and lost over time! If you destroyed the Room of Requirement, for example, it's likely it could never be restored again — that's why you're not going to break into it!"

"I'm going to do what I have to, to bring Potter in!" Malfoy shouted back. "And he's going to find that out, right now!" He stepped close to the wall, then brought his wand up to his throat and cast Sonorus. He spoke, his amplified voice ringing throughout the corridor. "Attention, occupants of the Room of Requirement. This is Head Auror Malfoy of the Ministry of Magic. You are hereby ordered to come out immediately."

There was no response, but Malfoy hadn't really expected on. "If you do not comply immediately, we will be forced to close down the school at once until you do comply. All students will be dismissed and a permanent squad of Aurors will stand guard at the entrance until you surrender yourself to us."

"Closing the school?" Neville said after uncovering his ears, when Malfoy finished speaking. "Is that really necessary?"

Malfoy pulled the wand away from his throat. "Without breaking down the wall, it's the best idea I've got. Don't forget, Headmaster, you have a reason to want them out of that room, too — I assume Potter didn't tell you he was planning to go in the Room of Requirement when he showed up here yesterday."

"No," Neville had to admit. "He said he was going to show Monroe the Chamber of Secrets."

"So he betrayed your trust," Malfoy pointed out. "And you, one of his Chaos Legionaires to boot."

"Save your manipulations, Malfoy," Neville growled, but there was an uneasy expression on his face. "Harry must've had a good reason."

"That's what I'm worried about," Malfoy muttered. He turned to his men. "Dawlish, you and Goyle remain here on guard. Don't let any students or staff in this corridor until I return." Both men nodded. "Crabbe, you and I are going back to headquarters, I want you to work out a schedule to have at least two men here round the clock until further notice. I'll work out the details of the closing with the Board of Governors of the school."

"I'm coming with you," Neville announced, firmly. "I've got some things to say to the Board of Governors about that."

"Suit yourself," Malfoy shrugged. He and Crabbe walked off, followed by the Headmaster, leaving Dawlish and Goyle alone in the corridor.

=ooo=

It was several minutes before anyone spoke again in the seventh-floor corridor. Goyle had shaken his head after Malfoy and the others left, then took up a position near the wall across from the tapestry, but after a minute shook his head again and conjured a stool to sit on.

Dawlish watched this as he leaned against the same wall a short distance away, one eyebrow raised in a silent commentary. Goyle noticed this but pretended not to; he didn't care much for Dawlish, who was often overly critical of younger Aurors. When he and Crabbe had finally been admitted to Auror Training, after spending time with a private tutor who made sure they passed the requisite number of N.E.W.T.s needed during a special test session of the Examination Authority, Dawlish had been their squad instructor. Training under him had not been pleasant.

"What?" Goyle finally said, annoyed at the half-smirk on the older Auror's face.

Dawlish shook his head. "Nothing, son," he said with a shrug, but a moment later added, "I just noticed that Crabbe once again got the nod from the Head over you. That seems to happen quite a bit, doesn't it?"

"Not a big deal," Goyle said. "Vinnie's got seniority." But not by much, Goyle reminded himself.

"Well, if you're okay with it." Dawlish looked left and right down the corridor they were in. "Students will be up and about soon," he noted. "This wasn't a highly-used section of the seventh floor in my day, but there are staircases to other level accessible through this corridor — we should start getting some traffic soon."

"Well, you're the senior Auror here," Goyle pointed out. "How d'you want to handle it?"

Dawlish pointed down the corridor. "Most students will be coming from that direction," he said. "Go round the corner to the first intersection and stand guard there. Tell students this corridor is blocked until further notice. I'll do the same at the other end."

Goyle folded his arms across his chest. "The Head wanted us remain here on guard," he reminded Dawlish.

"He also said don't let any students or staff in this corridor until he returned," Dawlish countered. "We can't stay here and do that as well. Don't worry, son, I'll take full responsibility."

Goyle smirked at the older Auror's attempt at manipulation, but shrugged and walked off down the corridor in the direction Dawlish had pointed.

When Goyle rounded the corner, Dawlish pointed his wand in that direction and softly spoke two Charms — a Silencing Charm and an Anti-Wizard Charm. Goyle would not hear anything coming from this corridor; if he tried to return he would experience a compulsion to move away, just as Muggles did when they ran into a Muggle-Repelling Charm. He cast the same two charms at the other end of the corridor.

An unpleasant sensation was beginning to well up inside Dawlish. The hour was almost up, he knew — it was good he'd gotten rid of Goyle when he did, and that Malfoy and Longbottom had gone back to the Ministry. The hardest part of this mission was about to get underway.

=ooo=

"Anything yet?" Monroe finally asked, after a minute or more of silence in the Room of Requirement.

"No," Harry muttered irritably. "Stop pestering me!"

"Harry, we've got to come up with something," Monroe persisted, ignoring Harry's irritation. "We don't want Malfoy knowing we've found a way around the Interdict, and we certainly don't want him talking to these statues!"

"I know all that!" Harry snapped. "I did the same Memory Enhancing ritual you did! We memorized all the Interdicted spells in these books —" he gestured at the pile of old books on the table before them. "There ought to be something we can do to get out of here!"

"There undoubtedly is," Monroe agreed. "But we're just not seeing it."

Dozens of powerful spells were swimming around in their brains now: how to perform Permanent Transfiguration and Conjuration spells, how to summon objects from anywhere, instantly, if you knew where it was. Spells that would make you immune to almost any magical disease or illness, or allow you to extend the lifetime of a normal wizard by three or four times. Spells to cure near- and farsightedness or hearing loss, and rituals that extend those senses well beyond the limit of human ability, though those rituals would shorten your life significantly — sacrifice for gain being a necessary part of any ritual.

"Maybe they can," Harry said, pointing to the four statues of the Founders. He addressed them once again. "O Founders, can you tell us of a way to leave this room and Hogwarts without disturbing any of the wards on the castle or grounds? This is something we very much need to do."

"We Founders created this Room as a place of final refuge here at Hogwarts," the statue of Rowena Ravenclaw spoke. "Wards do not penetrate this room, nor can any scyring or detection perceive it.

"But the rest of the castle is dedicated to the will of the current Headmaster; it is protected however he or she sees fit to do so. The current headmaster has added a new protection, one that perceives the mind of any sentient being within its range, and can describe and show where that being is on a representation of the castle's construction."

Harry was dumbfounded. "You mean like a map?" he asked, in shock.

"Yes," Gryffindor's statue answered. "Similar to the one you carry in your bag of holding."

Monroe raised an eyebrow. "How did you —"

"That tricky bastard," Harry said, though he was grinning now. "Neville added a Marauder's Map to the castle security! I wonder if he got Fred and George to do that for him — they were the only ones who know what that Map could do, other than Dumbledore himself."

"Does Neville know where we are now?" Monroe asked, nervously. It wasn't clear whether he was asking Harry or the Founders.

"Maybe not," it was Harry who answered. "If you're in the Room of Requirement you're not visible on the Marauder's Map, so if he asked his version of the Map it wouldn't show either of us. I suppose the question then is, would he wonder whether we're in the Room or not?"

"Would Malfoy?" Monroe asked.

"Crap," Harry muttered. "Of course he would, if Neville told him about the new security system. Malfoy knows the Room exists, and I'm pretty sure he knows about my Marauder's Map, much as I wished he didn't."

There was a long pause.

"So," Monroe finally spoke again. "We need a way to get out of this room and out of Hogwarts without alerting the new security system or passing through any part of the school outside this room. You know, that seems like a rather simple answer: Portkey."

"No," Harry immediately objected. "We would have to Portkey entirely out of Britain — remember , the Ministry can track unauthorized Portkey use anywhere in Britain now."

"I didn't know that," Monroe said. "When did that start?"

"Lord Malfoy got it pushed through the Ministry last month," Harry replied. "Draco wrote the law, of course. They saw it as a way to hurt me, to keep me from traveling back and forth between here and Europe, looking for Interdict-protected spell books."

"I thought you already had all the Interdict-protected spell books between Britain and the Far East," Monroe said, and Harry smiled.

"Most of them," he agreed. "Malfoy has most of the rest, I'd bet — he's been scrounging them up nearly as long as I have, mostly trying to figure out what I'm doing with them."

"Interesting," Monroe said, though he didn't sound particularly interested at the moment. "But this isn't helping us figure out a way out of here. So if we can't Portkey to anywhere in Britain, what about somewhere in Europe or Scandinavia, or even America?"

Harry pondered that for a moment. It seemed like a good idea…but his newly-eidetic memory finally settled on a detail. "But we'll still have to get back into Britain, and we won't be able to use a Portkey — we'll have to come in using another mode of transportation. Brooms would take too long, and we'll be recognized if we arrange for Floo travel or Apparate through Iceland." Reykjavík was a well-known stopover between the Americas and Britain and the European and Scandinavian Wizarding communities; it was also extensively warded to protect against unauthorized wizard travel.

"It sounds like we're stuck here, then," Monroe threw up his hands. "Are Malfoy and his men still outside the room?"

"I'll check." Harry recast the powerful detection spell that let him see through the wall. "Hmm — no, there's only one person out there now, and he — no, she, is on the floor for some reason… what the hell?" Harry turned to Monroe. "Holy crap, it's Ginny!"

"Ginny?!" Monroe was as shocked as Harry. "How'd she get in here? And where are Malfoy and his men?"

Harry shook his head, still watching as Ginny picked herself off the floor and turned to the wall between them. She put her wand up to her throat and said in a magically-amplified voice, "Harry? James? Are either of you in there? Can you hear me?"

Harry put his own wand to his throat and silently cast Sonorus. "We're here, Ginny! How'd you find us?"

"How about letting me in before Malfoy or one of his men come back and find me out here?" she asked.

Harry gesture and Monroe opened the door to the Room, letting Ginny step inside. She was breathing heavily and rubbing her forehead. "Thanks," she said as she stepped past Monroe and into the room.

"Are you okay?" Harry asked her, concerned. "You look a bit pale."

"Okay," she nodded. "Just the effects of Polyjuice wearing off. I was pretending to be someone else so I could walk through the castle unnoticed."

"I saw," Harry told her. "I was watching you just a minute ago, you were in the middle of changing form."

"Oh?" Ginny looked at the wall, then back at Harry. "What, did you finally figure out how to add X-ray vision to your glasses, then?" At that moment she noticed the four statues of the Founders and fell silent.

"No, no, it's a spell from one of these books," Harry said excitedly, picking up one of the ancient leather-bound volumes. "See what we found?" He pointed to the statues she was staring at. "The Founders put some of their essence into these four statues, and they can talk to us!"

"Like Horcruxes," Ginny said quietly. "Are you sure it's a good idea, talking to them, Harry?"

"No, they aren't Horcruxes," Harry averred. "They insisted they didn't use that ritual to create these statues."

"And you believed them?" Ginny said, giving Harry a skeptical look.

"Yes, I believed them!" Harry said, indignant. "They've helped us learn a lot of new spells since we've come here. Spells from before the Interdict of Merlin! Powerful spells, a lot more powerful than the most powerful spells we have today."

"So you've found a way round the Interdict, then," Ginny said, thoughtfully. "Congratulations, Harry! I know you've been looking for that for a long time."

"James actually found them," Harry said, pointing to Monroe. "I left him here when I came to help you out at TBC yesterday."

"Oh, so you were here, then?" Ginny asked. "The Aurors came round last night after dinner, asking questions about a letter Malfoy received that suggested you were visiting the Chamber of Secrets here at Hogwarts."

"Did they?" Harry frowned, hearing that. "I only told you we were doing that, Ginny."

"I had lunch with Ron on Saturday," Ginny explained. "I may have mentioned it to him. The Auror interrogating me asked a lot of questions about Ron and the letter. I think they suspected him of writing it."

"Ron." Harry's voice was tight. "I knew he didn't like me, but I didn't think he'd stoop to informing on me."

"It looks that way," Ginny said, apologetically. "I'm sorry, Harry. I've told him some things over the past few months, but I didn't know he was giving that information to the Ministry! I don't think Ron has any proof, though, beyond what I may have told him."

"Finding proof is what Malfoy does," Harry growled. "Whether he has to make it up or not. No wonder he's been after me so hard these past few months!"

"We should get out of here, you know," Ginny said, looking at the table filled with books and the four statues of the Founders. "But it's just so amazing that you've found a way to beat the Interdict! How did you do it?"

"She's right," Monroe put in. "We should get out of here while we have the chance."

"We found out that the Founders statues can read spells from these books!" Harry said, proudly, ignoring Monroe.

"So you just show them a spell and they read it to you," Ginny surmised.

"If they can," Harry nodded. "Not all of them know every spell, but I think there were only one or two spells none of them knew."

"That's very interesting," Ginny said, looking at the books on the table. "But you couldn't have memorized them all in this short a time, could you?"

"We were lucky," Harry grinned. "One of the spells we found straightaway was a Memory-Enhancing Ritual. Monroe and I both performed it, it seemed like a quick way to memorize all the spells, and the best thing was, there was no sacrifice required for it."

Ginny raised an eyebrow. "There's almost always a sacrifice during a ritual, Harry. Dark rituals require it, and most other rituals involve a sacrifice of some sort, even a small one."

"The Slytherin statue read that one to us," Monroe remembered. "He didn't say anything about a sacrifice."

Ginny picked up a book from the table and began flipping through the pages. She held out the book toward Harry. "Is that the spell he read to you?" she asked, pointing to a spell at the bottom of the page.

Harry looked. "Right," he said. "That's the one."

Ginny flipped to the next page. "What's it say at the top there?"

Harry peered at the words for several seconds. They were gibberish. "I can't read it," he said, looking up at her with a puzzled expression.

Ginny shook her head sadly. "That's probably where the sacrifice is mentioned," she said, looking at Harry with concern. "You didn't have him read the entire ritual." She walked over to the statue of Salazar Slytherin. "Read this," she commanded, pointing to the text Harry couldn't read.

There was silence for several seconds, but the Slytherin statue finally began to read.

Beware ye casters, who seek to improve thy recollection,
A price to be paid for the skillfulness of thy reflections,
Though ye shall remember all that ye have learned
Yet your wisdom shall be halved, never to be returned.

Harry and Monroe looked at each other, aghast. "Shit," Harry breathed. "That's why it's been so hard to figure out what to do!"

"Harry, I'm so sorry," Ginny said, looking as devastated as Harry felt.

"Never mind that now," Harry said, grimly. "We need to get out of here, now, before Malfoy returns and finds us here. Even if he can prove we were in the castle, we had permission to be here. And nobody can prove we were inside the Room of Requirement unless they come across the exact room we were in, and that's pretty unlikely."

"The question is, how do we do that?" Monroe asked. "If the staff's been alerted to our presence here they're not going to let us walk without trying to stop us."

"I think I have a way," Ginny said. "Harry, do you have your Cloak of Invisibility?"

"In my pouch," Harry nodded. "And the Marauder's Map. We can sneak out beneath it, is that what you're thinking?"

"Not really," Ginny disagreed. "The staff will be looking for something like that. I think we'll have to be rather bold, to do something unexpected, to get by them."

"Like what?" Both Harry and Monroe said at the same time.

"I've got some Polyjuice with me," Ginny replied, taking the bottle from her robes. "Have you noticed yet that my robes are for someone a bit larger than me?"

Harry's eyes looked Ginny up and down. "I guess they are," he said at last. "Whose clothes are they, anyway?"

"You'll see," Ginny smiled. "But first, get out your Cloak and the Map, and give the Map to me." Harry handed over the Map, waiting to hear what her plan was.

"You and Monroe get under the Cloak," Ginny ordered, and Harry threw the silvery material over himself and James. Ginny then held up the bottle of Polyjuice as if toasting them. "Cheers," she said, and downed the contents of the bottle, grimacing at the taste. "Eurgh, that's nasty," she muttered, then clutched her stomach as the potion began to take effect.

A minute later she stood transformed before them, a tall, stern-faced man with short, gray hair. Harry recognized him as an Auror, and wondered to himself how she'd gotten a bit of him for the Polyjuice. He'd have to ask her later, he decided, when they weren't in such a rush.

Ginny took out her wand and tapped the blank parchment in her hand, saying, "I solemnly swear that I am up to no good," in a deeper, more gruff-sounding voice than her own. Lines began forming across the parchment, showing the Marauder's Map, and the stern-faced Auror who Ginny had become studied it for several moments before folding it closed again.

"Ready?" Ginny asked the air. Harry and Monroe both nodded, then Harry realized they were invisible beneath the Cloak.

"Ready," he said aloud, and Ginny-the-male-Auror turned and opened the door, leading them out into the corridor.

=ooo=

Eileen Weatherly, the fifth year Hufflepuff prefect guarding the third floor area near the staircase leading down to the second floor, stifled a tired yawn. She hadn't gotten much sleep this night, between the alarm that had sounded earlier, just after midnight, and arrival of the team of Aurors not long ago that had prompted the Headmaster to put all the prefects and staff on alert.

But the idea that she might come across Harry Potter was exciting. She might not have a chance against him directly, but she could call the entire faculty down on him if need be — it was doubtful even Harry Potter himself could prevail against every teacher in the school. She only had to hope that the old caretaker, Filch, wouldn't be the first one to show up, or they were in deep dragon dung.

Bored, she conjured a bit of parchment and wrote a quick note on it with the tip of her wand. Hey Jimmy (her fellow prefect, James Brandson) see any sign of Potter yet? I bet I catch him before you do! Smiling, she tapped the parchment with her wand, and it folded itself into a bird-shape, then flew off to where Brandson was patrolling. That should work him up a bit, she thought. She and Jimmy were very good friends as well as prefects, but there was also a bit of Ravenclaw competitiveness in them — both had learned that the Sorting Hat had offered them Ravenclaw as well as Hufflepuff, but they had each preferred the friendliness of Helga Hufflepuff's House to the intellectual in-fighting of the House of Ravenclaw.

A sound reached her from the still dimly-lit corridor where she'd just sent the paper bird to Jimmy; it was past dawn by now but the sun still wasn't high enough in the sky to light the halls of the school adequately. "Who's there?" Eileen asked, raising her wand as Lumos-generated light shone from it.

"John Dawlish, Ministry Auror," a gruff voice replied, and a tall, gray-haired man stepped into the light of her wand. "And who are you, young lady?" he asked, stopping several feet from her, his wand at his side but ready to use, Weatherly noticed.

"I'm Eileen Weatherly," she said, a bit awed by the man's presence. "I—I thought the Aurors had left the school."

"The Head did," the man replied, his voice rough. "We're still trying to find Potter and his accomplice, James Monroe. Have you seen any sign of either of them?" he asked in an authoritative tone.

"Um, no," Eileen replied quickly. "I mean, no, sir," she added, remembering to address adults respectfully.

And then she saw something that made her flinch with horror. A small paper bird was fly toward her — Jimmy had replied to her not, but what a hell of a time for it to happen! The bird had almost reached the Auror when he turned suddenly, pointing his wand at the magical note. It stopped in mid-air, then fluttered into his hand. He tapped it with his wand; it unfolded and he began reading it.

Eileen wished she could crawl away and died. "My — er, my fellow prefect and I sometimes keep in touch that way, whenever we're separated," she said, uncomfortably, wishing she could vanish the parchment from the Auror's hand.

A small smile passed across the man's stern features. "It's alright, Miss, I'm not going to report you to the Headmaster. But stay ready and be prepared to react instantly if you see anything out of the ordinary." He took out a large piece of parchment that had been hidden within his robes. "I'm going outside the grounds so I can call in my notes to the Head, but I'll be back in a while. Stay vigilant," he finished, throwing her a salute.

Eileen, beaming, saluted in reply, and the tall Auror nodded and moved past her, down the staircase and out of sight in the dimness of the second floor. She continued beaming, hoping she could spend a few moments with him when he returned. Maybe she should look into being an Auror herself, she thought excitedly.

Outside the gates of Hogwarts, which had been unlocked by Hagrid before going inside the castle for breakfast, Harry, Monroe and Ginny quietly considered their next move. "Now what?" Harry asked, his and Monroe's heads peeking out from the Invisibility Cloak.

"Well, you can't go home, that's for sure," the form of John Dawlish said, rubbing his chin thoughtfully. "Malfoy will have a warrant to search your home by now, I suspect."

"I wish I could talk to Hermione," Harry muttered. "She'd know what we should do."

"Don't be an idiot," Ginny-Dawlish laughed scornfully. "You don't want to get her mixed up in this fiasco. We're — you're going to need all the help she can give you as Minister of Magic."

"Oh, yeah," Harry agreed, embarrassed he hadn't thought of that.

"What are we going to do about the effects of that ritual?" Monroe wanted to know.

"Dunno," Ginny shrugged. "The book said it wasn't reversible, didn't it?"

"Yeah," Harry moaned. "It did. But maybe there's another ritual we can use to negate the effects of the Memory Enhancing ritual."

"Maybe," Ginny agreed. "But it's liable to be one of those Interdict-protected spells in one of your books, Harry."

Harry rubbed his head in frustration. "I wish I'd never seen that damned spell!" he cried out.

"Quiet!" Monroe tried to hush him. "We don't need anyone hearing us and coming to investigate!"

"I have a place you can stay," Ginny offered. "It's a small apartment in South London — I rented it a few months ago so I could spend a night away from Dean from time to time. Nobody knows about it but me — and now, you."

"Good idea," Harry said, gratefully. "Thanks."

Ginny smiled warmly at Harry. "Well, let's see what you think of this one, then. What if I go to your apartment and collect those spell books of yours, then sneak back into Hogwarts and have those statues read them to me? I can look for a spell to remove that Memory-Enhancing ritual from you and Monroe, and then I can teach the important spells I learn to you two. It'll be slower without the memory ritual, but at least you'd have your intelligence back."

Harry looked at Monroe. "What do you think?"

"It sounds good to me," Monroe agreed. "If there's any way to get our original intelligence back, I'm all for it!"

"That's settled, then!" Ginny said, happily. "Now just let me get under the Cloak with you two —" there was a few seconds of fumbling about as the tall, male figure slipped between Harry and Monroe. The figure of John Dawlish tapped himself with his wand, saying "Finite Bibotatem!" then doubled over, falling to the ground on his knees and transforming into Ginny Weasley once again. Harry and Monroe helped her to her feet, and she slipped her arms into theirs.

"Ready?" she asked. "On three, then." Three seconds later they were gone.

Chapter 26: Escape from Azkaban

Updated 3/15/2013

=ooo=

"Now," Harry declared forcefully. "We break out of here!" He then slumped to the floor next to Sirius. "As soon as I rest for a minute."

Sirius didn't answer or acknowledge Harry's statement. He still seemed to be thinking about Peter Pettigrew's death — his eyes, dark and sunken within their sockets, stared into nothingness.

For someone who had spent over 35 years in Azkaban, Harry reflected, Sirius Black looked amazingly well. He remembered what Bellatrix Black had looked like after only a decade — she had been more of a corpse than a woman, when Harry first saw her: eyes shrunken below their lids, lips so shriveled she might not have been able to close them over her teeth, and skin so pale and thin it might have been paper stretched over a skeleton. In comparison, with the draining effects of the Dementors removed by Harry's Patronus, Sirius should have been dancing around the cell right now.

A while later Harry asked, "Sirius? How do you feel?"

Sirius slowly blinked and managed a small shrug. "Better," he said, though his expression didn't change. "I don't feel them anymore." He blinked again in what was apparently confusion about what had just happened. "Where are we?"

"Still in Azkaban," Harry said, matter-of-factly. "But not for long — we're getting out of here."

"Getting out…of Azkaban?" Sirius repeated, slowly. "I — I don't know if that's even possible."

"Oh, I think it is," Harry muttered. "I just need a moment to figure out what to do."

"A moment?" Sirius at last looked up at Harry, a look of disbelief on his pale, emaciated face. "You're going to need a lot longer than a moment, Harry. I've been thinking about it since I got here, and I'm still here. Whatever you and your shining friend here are planning, it's probably not going to work."

It worked before, Harry thought, remembering the last time he was here, but he didn't have the resources that he did back then. He'd had his Invisibility Cloak, his mokeskin pouch filled with useful items — and a brilliant Defense Against the Dark Arts professor who was highly motivated to escape without detection.

What did he have now? A wand taken from a now-dead traitor and a man who'd been a prisoner here for 35 years. Plus, he also remembered, his own mind and body were crippled because of spells that had been placed on him before he'd come here. One of those he'd unfortunately cast upon himself, but the other one was the work of Voldemort, who'd been possessing the body of Ginny Thomas.

And Ginny was in Azkaban, too, Harry recalled, sent here for the death of three Aurors that Voldemort had murdered while possessing her body. He would have to find her, too, and get her out of here.

"It'll work," Harry insisted stubbornly.

"What's your plan, then?" Sirius asked, doubtfully.

"No idea," Harry said. "I'm still thinking."

"Perhaps I can be of assistance," another voice spoke. The voice had been Harry's, though. Harry looked up in surprise — it had come from his Patronus!

Sirius was staring up at the shining humanoid as well. "Who's this supposed to be?" he asked. "I didn't think ghosts lasted long in Azkaban — the Dementors drain them, too. They either leave or eventually they disappear."

"He's not a ghost," Harry said distractedly. Why had his Patronus spoken? Harry hadn't told him to say anything. "He's my Patronus."

Sirius snorted derisively. "No it's not," he said, disbelievingly. "Patronuses are animals, not humans."

"I am a Patronus," Harry's Patronus said, directly to Sirius. "Harry has several unique abilities, among them the ability to produce a True Patronus such as myself."

"Why are you able to speak?" Harry asked. "I didn't think even my Patronus had the ability to speak other than to repeat what I've told you to say."

"It has been some time since you've produced me," the Patronus answered. "In fact, since before you left Hogwarts. But I have always been within you — growing, learning, maturing. I know much has happened to you in just the past few months."

Harry nodded. Looking at his Patronus now, he saw that it was more than a mere humanoid shape. He could see feature on it — lips, a nose, and even a silvery mop of disheveled hair much like Harry had when he was younger. "You even look a bit like me, now," he said.

"Yes, but unlike you, I do not suffer from the same disadvantages you do. I have no physical body — my corporeal form is mere appearance — but my mind is the equivalent of yours without the disadvantages the Memory Enhancing Ritual imposed upon it. I have your full intelligence and memory, and I share your desire to leave this place."

Harry nodded again. "Good," he said. "I've been remembering things since I produced you — is that because I'm no longer feeling the Dementors' influence?"

"It is, to a degree," the Patronus answered. "But I have also been returning some of your memories to you — they were erased by Voldemort with a Memory Charm; you would not have remembered them except for my retention of them — I am not susceptible to such Charms."

Sirius, who had been silent since learning the glowing, silvery human was not a ghost, but Harry's Patronus, finally spoke again. "Maybe I've been in here too long, but I don't understand a bloody thing either of you are saying!"

"Probably not," Harry agreed, "but it would take too long to explain right now. Our first priority should be getting out of here and finding a safe place for us to stay and recuperate." He looked at his Patronus. "Do you have any ideas?"

His Patronus nodded slowly. "I have been considering our escape. Do you think you can cast a Portkey spell capable of reaching northern Scotland?"

"That won't work," Sirius said immediately. "You can't leave or enter Azkaban with a Portkey."

Harry knew that as well, but why would his Patronus suggest it in the first place? "He's right, you know," he said to his silvery doppleganger.

"There is one place in Azkaban where magic does not, can not persist," the Patronus said. "In the nest of Dementors at the bottom of the prison, in its core."

Sirius barked a laugh. "For good reason! Nobody can go down there without going catatonic! Even if every Auror in this place sent their Patronuses down with you, you couldn't stand to be there more than a minute or two before the Dementors would drain you of every last bit of happiness and magic! Harry, you can't seriously be thinking of trying something as stupid as that, even with this Patronus of yours! Like Shiny Bloke said, magic doesn't work there anyway!"

Harry saw what his Patronus was suggesting. "But if the Dementors weren't there," he pointed out, "the wards preventing a fast exit from Azkaban wouldn't be in effect either, and we could create a Portkey and get out of here."

"There are something like 80 or 100 Dementors down there," Sirius argued. "You might hold them off for a bit, but some of them would be bound to grab you and — and — K-Kiss you…" He shuddered involuntarily. "They would, you know — just to be rid of your Patronus. They prefer to do it slowly, though, to drain you a bit at a time, enjoying the taste of your happiness."

"Bollocks," Harry said.

Sirius looked affronted. "I've been here a lot bloody longer than you have, Harry — I ought to know how they think by now!"

"Dementors don't think," Harry retorted. "They never have. Wizards just anthropomorphize them because they see a humanoid shape and think that a human-like shape means a human-like mind. That's not true."

"They've spoken to me!" Sirius snarled. "Don't tell me they don't speak, Harry! They've taunted me for as long as I've been here, reminding me that I'm here because my own kind turned against me, threw me in here without a fair trial just to be rid of me, to tie up a messy end now that Voldemort was destroyed! And they were wrong, weren't they!?" he shouted, slamming his claw-like hands down on the steel floor. "Pettigrew's dead now, but he should have been in here, not me!"

"I'm not arguing that," Harry replied, calmly; he'd also remembered what happened the last time he'd let his emotions run away with him while in Azkaban. "But we have to think about getting out of here, not have a row over whether Dementors can speak or not. Do you agree?"

Sirius still looked angry, though he gave Harry the impression that most of his anger was still directed at himself, for killing Pettigrew, but he nodded curtly. "Yeah," he muttered at last. "Seeing how you and I found one another after all this time, Harry, I think we should get out of here if we can."

"Alright," Harry nodded. He looked back at his Patronus, who'd been waiting patiently during the argument, and asked, "What is your plan to get out of here?"

"We must first locate Ginny Thomas," the Patronus said. "Convicted of multiple murders, she is below this level, not far from us. We are in the C-spiral, third level of the prison. I would seek her out alone, but if I am not in your presence you will feel the effects of the Dementors once again. You both must go with me. After we find her we must travel to the bottommost level of the prison, where Harry will remove a section of the wall, revealing the nesting place of the Dementors, and I will deal with them."

"Sounds pretty simple, assuming you can pull it off," Sirius said skeptically. "But we've got a wand, now, so it shouln't be too hard to get out of here."

"It will work," Harry said, determinedly. "I don't know how long I've been in here, but this is the best chance we all have of getting out of here, and I'm not going to pass it up!"

=ooo=

The trek to the bottom of Azkaban began with the large iron padlock that secured the door of Harry's cell. A simple Alohomora was sufficient to open it; like nearly every other lock in the wizards' prison it had no wards to prevent magical unlocking spells from working on it — no spell meant to last any length of time could withstand the draining effect of the Dementors. Harry followed up that charm with a spell to remove the lock from the latch that kept the door from opening, and it fell to the metal floor of the corridor with a loud clang.

Harry winced at the noise, but he hadn't regained enough fine control yet to switch to a Levitation Charm in time to prevent the lock from falling. They would have to hope that the sound would not carry far enough through the metal structure to be heard on the top level of the prison where the Aurors guarding them were stationed.

He pushed the door open a fraction, and Sirius, now transformed back into the large, bearlike dog that was his Animagus form, softly padded into the corridor beyond to check out the situation. Harry had his Patronus move just past the doorway so that both he and Sirius remain within its silvery, protective light. As long as they were, they would be invisible to the Dementors — more than invisible, in fact: the Dementors would not even realize they were there anymore, just as they had not been able to see Bellatrix Black when she was bathed in his Patronus's light, back when he and Quirrell came to rescue her.

Sirius returned after perhaps two minutes, transforming back to human to report to Harry. "Not much going on out there; I think you and I were the only two still alive in this block of cells. I could hear someone screaming somewhere down the corridor."

The screaming had bothered Harry the first time he'd been here. It had been heart-wrenching, in fact. But he had only heard it after he'd screwed up their chances of escaping Azkaban without being noticed. And it had been Sirius's cousin Bellatrix that had caused him to do it.

But that had been long ago, from an eleven-year old boy who hadn't really thought about the sheer horror a place like Azkaban could generate within him. Now it was a quarter-century later, and Harry was much better versed in the ways of the world than he had been back then. Azkaban was still a horror, one Harry hoped to end one day, but it wasn't going to cause him to lose control.

If he did what his Patronus had seemed to imply, once they were at the base of the tower, he would make serious progress toward the ending of Azkaban.

"Let's go," Harry said, softly, and Sirius, Harry and his Patronus stepped into the corridor. They were in a block of eight cells, one of several along this side of the three-sided structure, and Harry had been in the cell nearest to the inner wall; on the other side was the central core of the tower, open at the top. At the bottom of that open shaft was the nest of Dementors — a layer of dirt that had to be regularly replaced because the presence of the Dementors caused it to dissolve into nothingness over time.

The corridor they were in was dimly lit in orange light coming from gas lamps set along either side of the block. They moved slowly to the end of the corridor, where another locked steel door blocked their way. Harry made short work of that lock as well, catching it this time before it hit the floor.

Then they were in the outer corridor, the one leading along one edge of the huge hollow triangular tower. In the silvery light of his Patronus Harry could see three other metal doors set along the corridor, all on the same side. The opposite side of the corridor was a solid steel wall. At either end were the steel doors that led to staircases going up or down along the spiral they were in. Now for the next order of business…

"Do you know where Ginny is?" Harry asked his Patronus.

The Patronus seemed to smile slightly before it answered. "Of course," it said. "However, she is not in this spiral. We must find a way to the A-spiral, and two levels further down."

"Nearly halfway to the Dementors," Sirius muttered. "How long has she been in here?"

"As long as me," Harry said, "but I don't know how long I've been here."

"You have been incarcerated here for 37 days," his Patronus interjected.

"That's all?" It had seemed like months to Harry — years, even. "Can you tell how she's doing?"

"Not without going to her," the Patronus answered. "If I leave you and Sirius you will experience the full effects of the Dementors once again. Sirius could change into his Animagus form, but you would be incapacitated after a few minutes. If they sense you are out of your cell they will come for you, and if I were not present they might choose to Kiss you."

"What if I cast my Patronus?" Sirius asked. "I feel better now, I think I can produce one."

"There is only one wand," the Patronus pointed out.

"Oh, yeah. Dammit!" Sirius slapped his forehead with the heel of his hand. "I guess I'm not thinking as well as I expected."

"You've been here longer," Harry said, almost gently. Then, suddenly realizing something, he turned to the Patronus. "Won't there be an Auror patrol coming through here soon?"

"I was just thinking that as well," the Patronus answered. "The Aurors patrolling this spiral will be bringing water as they renew the wards that are kept active to prevent unauthorized access to each level. They are scheduled to traverse this level in approximately 5 minutes. The patrols in the other levels will be moving in parallel. Fortunately, we are in the C-spiral, so the levels below us will be clear for approximately 15 minutes if we can get through to the A-spiral level below us."

"How difficult is that going to be?" Harry asked anxiously. His brain dimly remembered the ridiculous amount of constraints his last passage through Azkaban had been.

"It depends on how difficult it is to locate the secret passage between the levels," his Patronus answered.

"How do you know there's a secret passage?" Sirius asked, looking doubtful.

"Because this structure was built by wizards," the Patronus replied, its voice dry rather than the emotionless monotone it usually spoke with. "Secret passages are almost de rigeur, even for a prison where security is paramount. They will be keyed to the Aurors, of course — we may have difficulty locating them."

Sirius grinned crookedly. "I guess you're right about wizards and secret passages," he said. "I remember the fun we had whenever we found a new one in Hogwarts! James and I would have races to see who could get from Gryffindor Tower to the Great Hall the fastest —"

"Not to interrupt your fond memories," Harry said shortly, "but we should start looking for that secret passage if we're going to be gone when the Aurors get to this level."

"Right," Sirius looked around the corridor. "Which way do we go, then?"

"The spirals go downward clockwise from the top level," the Patronus said. "And the cells are toward the inward edge of each level, so that door—" it pointed the door on their right— "will lead us downward. However—" it then pointed to the door on the left. "I have a intuition we will find the passage to A-spiral in that direction."

"We should get cracking, then," Harry said, turning that way. "We have less than 5 minutes to find it before the Aurors arrive on this level."

The three of them — the shining figure of Harry's Patronus, the skeletally-thin Animagus, and perhaps the only other innocent man in Azkaban — made their way toward the door leading to the staircase that would take them upward to the next level of the spiral and closer to the Aurors who were approaching from that direction.

=ooo=

Three pairs of Aurors moved in parallel down the interleaved levels of Azkaban Prison's three spirals, each pair staying a bit behind the team in the level below them. This sweep was for water only, as well as to renew the spells preventing magical entry into and exit from the levels, both from outside and between levels of the prison itself. It would do no good if intruders could Apparate or Portkey between levels and spirals of the prison.

The procedure for this pass was simple: collect the numbered bowls left near the entrance of each cell block, then fill each bowl with water using Aguamenti and pass it through the door of the cell that corresponded to the number on the bowl. If there was an empty bowl near the door, take it to be placed at next to the block door. If a prisoner forgot to place their bowls next to the door they didn't get any more water; it was that simple. It didn't take the new prisoners long to figure it out.

Auror Xiaoguang (aka "Mike") Li, a veteran of Azkaban of nearly 20 years, had partnered with Auror Wilhelm Janssen, who had only recently been given duty at the prison. Wil was still unused to the unsettling effects of being so close to Dementors for an extended period of time; his silver cockatiel wavered unsteadily even though Li had him stay near the block door, as far from the Dementors as possible while still in view of both the cell block and the outside corridor. Li's own silver badger was emitting a soft, steady glow, protecting him and Janssen from the effects of the Dementors below.

Li returned with three water bowls, the current count of still-living prisoners in this block. By and large the prisoners managed to stay alive longer these days than they had when Li had first come to Azkaban. In those days, if you were put in the wizards' prison it was to do real hard time — hardly any prisoners had survived from those days. Li remembered stories he'd read in the Prophet about a twelve-year old girl the Wizengamot almost sentenced to Azkaban — she had gone on years later to become Minister of Magic. She had only recently resigned after her husband, Harry Potter, was sent to prison for murder. They would check on Potter in the next section of the spiral, along with the man who'd been here the longest of anyone: Sirius Black.

"Doing okay, Wil?" Li asked, coolly, as he stepped past Janssen and into the corridor beyond. Janssen nodded, looking pale.

"You'll get used to it," Li said as they walked to the last cell block in this section, casting Alohomora on the door's large iron padlock and removing it. He hung the open lock on the door and opened it. "Have any of your mates mentioned keeping your Patronus active as you sleep yet?"

"Y-yes," Janssen replied, his voice dubious. "But I didn't think you could maintain one while you were asleep."

"It's a bit tricky," Li conceded. He looked at the small shelf next to the door, where the water bowls were stored. Three bowls. He frowned. There were four prisoners in this block. Had Number Two forgotten to put his bowl by the door, or… "Most of us manage it, after some practice. You'll sleep better if your Patronus is next to you. Keeps the nightmares away." He filled Bowl One with water, then opened the small trapdoor at the bottom of the large steel door numbered One and slid the bowl inside. An empty bowl was next to the door; he Summoned it and put it on the bottom of the other bowls, then moved to cell Two.

Opening the trap door, he cast Homenum Revelio. There was a flash showing a human lying on the camp bed inside. And an empty bowl next to the door. Good — the prisoner had probably just forgotten earlier. Li Summoned the bowl then moved on, filling the other bowls and replacing the empty bowls with them.

When he returned to the cell block door, Janssen was giving him an expectant look, as if he wanted to say something. "What is it?" Li asked as he closed the door and relocked the padlock.

"Well," Janssen was looking toward the door leading to the stairs down to the next level. "This is the spiral that, um, Harry Potter is in, isn't it?"

A smile curled a corner of Li's mouth. "It took you long enough to ask me that, Wil. Yeah, Potter's on the next level, he's been here about a month now. You haven't been down to see him yet?"

Janssen shook his head. His cockatiel Patronus mirrored the gesture. "This is the first time I've gone down C-spiral," he said. "The other guys on my team have, uh, covered for me going on food and water runs. Er, to give me time to acclimate to the place."

Li nodded. "Yeah, this place can get to you if you let it. I've been doing tours here since 1990 and if it weren't for the triple-pay I'd walk away in a heartbeat. And it was ten times worse back in the 90's!"

"Worse?" Janssen's eyes widened. "Than now? You've got to be shitting me, Mike! This is the most awful place I've ever been in!"

"You can imagine how it is for the prisoners, then," Li pointed out. "We've only got one prisoner left from back then, and he's been here since 1981. He's on the next level, too, a bloke named Sirius Black."

"Since 1981?" Janssen looked horrified. "Merlin, that's over 35 years! How could anyone stand it here that long?"

"Some of us have wondered that as well," Li agreed. "We don't see much of Black — he doesn't lie on his bunk much. He prefers to curl up in a corner of the cell where we can't see him unless we go inside. We check up on him every so often, change out his blankets every six months or so. They're always covered with hair, though he's still got a full head of hair himself. Haven't quite worked that out, yet."

Li jerked a thumb at the door leading to the staircase down to the next level. "Let's keep moving. If you like I'll let you change out the water bowls in Potter and Black's cells. They're in the same block — for some reason, when Black heard that Harry Potter was in here he asked to be moved next to his cell. Nobody could think of a good reason why not, so we moved him.

"But…" Janssen had a thoughtful frown on his face. "Before I came here I read a book on the most famous prisoners in Azkaban over the centuries. People like Crispin Cronk, or Carlotta Pinkstone, and of course Bellatrix and Sirius Black. I remember reading that Black had something to do with the death of Harry Potter's parents."

Li shrugged indifferently. "I remember something about that — Black told his leader, the Dark Lord Voldemort, where the Potters were hidden so Voldemort could kill them. That was pretty treacherous but it's not the reason Black is in here. A day or so after the Potters died Black murdered a wizard in full view of witnesses on a London street. He killed twelve Muggles as well."

Janssen shook his head. "I don't think Harry Potter would want someone like Black anywhere near him, especially after all that."

"Well, if Harry Potter offers us a bribe to move him away from Black, we'll consider it," Li suggested. He patted Janssen on the shoulder. "For now, let's get cracking so we don't fall behind the other spirals. And remember, you're going to have a look at Harry Potter himself."

Janssen nodded, and his Patronus brightened fractionally. A chance to see Harry Potter-Evans-Verres-Granger himself! The two men moved toward the door at the end of the corridor, the one leading to a long, metal staircase to the next level down.

=ooo=

Harry and Sirius stared at the staircase leading up to the level above them. Every staircase to a new level of each spiral was located in a corner of the prison where two sides met. A short hallway led to each staircase, which led up or down (depending on which direction you were traveling in) along the inside of the outer wall of the prison, to a landing area, then continued along the adjacent wall to the next level

Somewhere in this area was a secret passage between the C- and A-spirals, if Harry's Patronus was correct. But they only had about four minutes to find it! "What do we look for?" Harry asked his Patronus.

"It will not be obvious, of course," the Patronus said, thoughtfully, looking around the hallway they were in. "I can search for it directly, if you do not mind me being out of sight for a little while."

"What about the Dementors?" Harry asked. "Won't they sense us if we're not protected by your light?"

"There is a small risk, but I will be out of your sight only a few seconds," the Patronus said. "Do you wish to risk it?"

"Go," Harry said immediately. "We don't have much time." The Patronus nodded and moved up the stairway, its protective light dimming as it moved away from them.

A pall of depression began to settle over Harry and Sirius. Sirius bent over, holding his head as if he'd suddenly developed a splitting headache. "Damn," he muttered. "I'd forgotten how bad that felt!"

"Yeah," Harry agreed, wincing at the near-pain he felt now that his Patronus was no longer protecting them from the Dementors' debilitating influence. He put his arms around himself, trying to hold in the vestiges of optimism and happiness he'd felt only moments earlier. "At least you can turn into your Animagus form and avoid the worst of this."

"But I won't," Sirius said, standing straighter again. "Not if you can't. Damn, I wish I had a wand! I could cast my own Patronus for us! I wish yours would hurry up and find that bloody secret passage already —"

"Up here," Harry's Patronus said suddenly from somewhere along the staircase. "Hurry, the Aurors are almost finished with the level above us."

Harry and Sirius scrambled up the staircase steps, feeling better as the approached the landing. The Patronus was there, standing next to a wall on the side nearest the outside corner. "It is here," it said, pointing to the wall. "But we are nearly out of time. Harry, you should cast Colloportus on the door at the top of the stairs, the two Aurors moving through this spiral are nearly ready to enter."

Harry nodded and moved up the staircase until he was almost at the top and he could see the large steel door leading to the level above them. He concentrated for a moment, then pointed the wand he held at the door and said, "Colloportus." There was a soft click as the lock in the door engaged. He moved back down the stairs to the landing.

"That won't hold them more than a few seconds," he said, looking at the wall his Patronus had indicated earlier. "Where's the passageway?"

"Just about here," the Patronus pointed to a section of the wall. You will need to cast Quarello's Discernment spell to reveal it."

Harry held up his wand, but shook his head a moment later. "I don't remember the words," he said, anxiously. "I know I should —"

It is 'Revelio Dex Ontoblum,'" the Patronus said. "You should hurry — the Aurors are about to enter the stairwell."

Harry nodded and drew a breath, then pointed his wand and repeated the words. There was no response. The handle on the door at the top of the staircase rattled, as if someone was trying to turn it.

"Try again!" Sirius urged. "Concentrate, Harry!"

"You concentrate," Harry muttered. He jerked as a hand touched him — his Patronus had placed its silver palm on his shoulder. That helped — the gestures and words of the charm suddenly appeared in his brain. "Revelio Dex Ontobulum!" he said softly, the tip of the wand tracing the correct pattern, and a small doorway appeared in the wall, just large enough for him and Sirius to squeeze through.

"Let's go," Harry whispered, and he and Sirius moved into the passage, pulling the cover closed behind them. The Patronus murmured words in Harry's ear and he pointed his wand at the cover and cast one more spell.

The inside of the passage was larger than Harry had expected, but it probably wasn't an Extension Charm — that would eventually dissipate if not kept up by the Aurors. Two staircases led away, one going up, the other going down, and Harry's Patronus moved into the one going down. Harry and Sirius immediately followed, moving as quietly as they could on the metal steps of the staircase.

=ooo=

"What the hell?" Li said, confused, as the door leading to the staircase down to the next level refused to open. "Nobody should have locked this!"

Janssen was looking around, suddenly alert. "Did you hear something? A clicking sound?"

"No," Li said, chagrinned. He'd been thinking about what Janssen would say when he saw Harry Potter for the first time. "Call it in to Control," he ordered. "We'll proceed on Level Two alert." That meant Anti-Disillusionment and Shield Charms in place, and Human Revealment spells cast ahead of them wherever someone might be hiding under an invisibility cloak. While Janssen called Upstairs to let them know there was a problem, Li put up his shields and cast the Anti-Disillusionment Charm on himself. Incidentally he cast Alohomora on the door in front of them and waved it open with his wand, casting Homenum Revelio on the landing and staircase. There was no one there, at least not between where they were and the landing of the staircase.

Janssen cast his own spells and the two of them moved slowly into the stairway and down the steps. Li cast a detection spell that showed human footprints and handprints — they had touched one wall of the landing. Li cast a spell on the area around the handprints, but the cover of the passageway between spirals, accessible only by use of an advanced detection spell, had not been opened recently. Breaking into Azkaban still wasn't that difficult, if you were good enough, but it still rankled Li that it had happened on his watch. After that fiasco in early '92 the Head had reamed out everyone on duty and docked them a week's pay. He didn't want another situation like that taking place again.

A thought came unbidden into his consciousness. It wasn't a happy thought, of course, but then most Aurors were pessimists at heart, he'd decided. What if Harry Potter and/or Sirius Black had escaped? Li grimaced, deciding to keep that potential disaster to himself for the moment.

"Let's see what's going on down there," he instead whispered to Janssen, and the two Aurors moved down the staircase to the next level below.

=ooo=

Harry and Sirius followed Harry's Patronus down the narrow, steep passageway. It curved tightly, making Harry think whoever had designed it had planned for very little extra room. The steel walls of the passage were cold and clammy; they must be very near the outer wall of the prison. Briefly, Harry wondered if they could simply break out right here, but remembered why they were going to A-spiral: to rescue Ginny. Ginny, who never should have ended up in Azkaban the first place except that Voldemort had used her against him. All those years he must've hidden himself away within her body, waiting for the moment to reassert himself. Not a pleasant thought. But then, when you were in Azkaban such thoughts were commonplace.

They reached a small landing where another set of steps branched off, continuing to spiral downward, and a short corridor leading to a blank wall. Harry's Patronus stood aside, gesturing for Harry to step forward.

"You must cast Quarello's Discernment again to open this cover," the Patronus told him. "Once we are in A-spiral I will lead us directly to Ginny Thomas's cell."

Harry cast the spell again and the cover popped open. He and Sirius piled out onto the landing, and the Patronus appeared next to them a moment later. "Remember to shut the cover and cast the spell erasing our use of the passageway." Harry complied, then the three of them moved down the staircase to the door below, the letters 5-A stenciled next to it.

"Halfway down the tower," Sirius muttered. "What did this Ginny Thomas do?"

"Nothing," Harry said grimly. "But she was convicted of murdering three Aurors."

Sirius whistled, though it was more like a shrill sigh than a whistle. "I'm surprised she's not deeper in the prison, then — the Aurors here don't treat Auror-killers well at all. I'm supposed to have killed thirteen people, including a wizard, and I'm two levels above her."

Now out in the corridor for this level, the Patronus pointed unerringly to the third block door. "She is there, in the cell closest to the inner wall and the Dementors. Things are not well with her — I can barely sense her presence."
Harry moved forward, striding purposefully to the third door along the corridor. As he approached the door his wand went out, pointing at the padlock on the door; it broke apart and fell to the floor with a clang. The door flew open and Harry went through without breaking stride, Sirius and Harry's Patronus hurrying after him.

When Sirius and the Patronus reached the block door Harry was already striding down the corridor to the farthest cell doors. "Right or left?" he said over his shoulder, to his Patronus.

"The left," the Patronus answered, and the lock on that door shattered a moment later. Harry stepped into the doorway — and halted.

"That bastard," he breathed a moment later, his gaze frozen by what he saw inside. "That fucking bastard."

Ginny Thomas lay sprawled like a broken doll across a worn and weathered cot in the corner of the cell. Her red hair, normally resplendent with color, seemed withered and gray. Her clothing, the same clothing she had been in the last time Harry saw her, was already beginning to go tattered and torn. She had not moved since Harry entered the room; the only motion he saw was the rising and falling of her chest as she breathed.

Harry moved quickly over to her, lifting her head and laying it in his lap as he sat down on the cot. Harry looked up, gesturing to his Patronus to come closer at once. The Patronus complied, and as its light shone on her Ginny heaved one shuddering sigh. Her eyes flickered, focusing on Harry's face.

"I knew you would come for me," she whispered hoarsely, then closed her eyes again.

"Yes, I'm here," Harry whispered, not knowing what else to say. He cupped her cheek in his hand, feeling an impulse to kiss her, but Prince Charming he wasn't; an Innervate would do more good for her than a kiss.

Sirius stepped in front of them. "Let me take her," he said, softly. "We've got to go — we've got four more levels before we reach the bottom of Azkaban."

Harry let Sirius lift her body off the cot. He hardly looked capable of standing by himself, but he held her easily.

"We should move briskly," the Patronus said. "If the Aurors discover you are no longer in your cells they will go on alert and institute a lockdown on all levels. It will be difficult to move from level to level with a lockdown in place, and we must reach the bottom in order to escape."

Harry nodded then stood, trembling with repressed anger. He was going to kill Voldemort for this, no matter what he had to do to find that last Horcrux and destroy it. "Let's go," he ordered. "We're getting out of here, no matter what comes after us now."

=ooo=

Li and Janssen moved carefully into the fourth level of C-spiral, checking for any Disillusioned people lurking in shadows and casting Homenum Revelio to check for cloaks. The footprints they had detected showed unusual activity. One set of footprints had come up the stairs almost to the door of the level they had just left, but had turned and went down again. Two sets of footprints had come up to the landing of the staircase they had just left, but had ended there. It almost looked as if they had gone into the passageway between spirals, but they'd checked and the detection spells said the door hadn't been opened. Human Revealment and Anti-Disillusionment Charms showed no one had been hiding in the staircase. If the intruders had somehow realized Li and Janssen were approaching them and backtracked, they might be hiding on this level after somehow erasing or disguising their footprints. If not, then they were moving lower and lower into Azkaban, and that was never a good direction to go in, not without serious Patronus protection.

At least, Li hoped that what the indications meant. If not… well, Li's memories of the last breakout of Azkaban still came to mind. Amelia Bones was no longer head of the DMLE, but Minister Malfoy hadn't yet appointed a replacement, which mean that he would be in charge if they had to elevate this any higher. And Li did not want to be around if that happened.

Janssen was tracing the footprints they could detect back along their path. "They seem to be angling toward Block Two," he murmured, and Li groaned inwardly. Black and Potter's cell block.

"Look at the padlock on the block door," Li said a moment later. "It doesn't look right." As they moved nearer they saw why: the padlock was dangling from the handle of the door instead of the latch that secured it.

"Shit," Li said softly. "Call it in. Tell them to lock it down!" There was not going to be a repeat of the day Bellatrix Black escaped, he told himself again. Malfoy would have to be called in, but they would cross that bridge when they got to it.

=ooo=

Harry remained silent as they moved down the levels of A-spiral toward the bottommost level, number Nine. He was still repressing the anger he'd felt when he'd found Ginny, semi-starved and nearly dead from exposure to Dementors. Shortly, though, he would be able to let his anger out, and things would forever change at Azkaban Prison.

He was not angry at the Aurors who'd likely mistreated her, though he was not going to go easy on them if they got in his way. They believed Ginny had murdered three of their own; it was normal to feel anger and hatred toward someone who'd done something like that. It was personal to them, unlike Harry's supposed murder of James Monroe, a man none of them had known and who was simply another face in the Wizarding community. They'd treated Harry like they would any other murderer. But for Ginny, it had been three of their own.

Except that Ginny had not murdered the three Aurors, Harry now remembered. It had been Voldemort possessing her body who had committed those murders. Voldemort, who was now in the body of Draco Malfoy, who had schemed and manipulated his way to the Ministry after ousting his wife, Hermione. Hermione had resigned after Harry was arrested for the murder of Monroe, but it had been Voldemort pulling the strings once again.

Now that Harry remembered these things, there was nothing that could keep him in Azkaban, slowly rotting away for a crime he didn't commit. Ginny would be leaving with him as well, as would Sirius Black who, it turned out, had not killed Peter Pettigrew back in November 1981. Pettigrew had pretended to die in an explosion that killed twelve innocent people, leaving his right index finger as the only part of him left after the explosion, and gone into hiding. While Harry was in Azkaban Pettigrew snuck into his cell using the ventilation system and pretended to be one of Harry's "voices." In Harry's demented state it had been quite convincing, until Sirius, who'd been moved into the cell next to him, switched cells with Harry and captured Pettigrew, proving he was alive.

Pettigrew was dead now, however, after attacking Sirius with a knife and trying to escape. Sirius had transformed into his dog Animagus and shaken Peter to death. His body was still back in Harry's old cell, the only proof that he'd escaped death back in 1981, but the other rats in Azkaban (the real rats) would make short work of his body, and the physical proof of Sirius's innocence would be lost.

Harry had almost considered turning around to retrieve the rat's body, so at least Sirius would be able prove he hadn't committed murder, but time was running out. The Aurors moving through the levels would discover that he and Sirius were gone any moment now, and they needed to be at the lowest level of the prison before that happened; the doors between levels would become much harder to open once Azkaban went into lockdown.

They had traveled down three levels in as many minutes. Entering the ninth level Harry pointed toward the first block door, intending to remove the padlock. The doors were locked whether anyone was in the cells or not, and his Patronus had told him no one was imprisoned below Level Five in any spiral. Before he could remove the lock, however, the dim orange light of the gas lamps suddenly snuffed out, leaving only the silvery light of Harry's Patronus.

"Lockdown," Sirius whispered, looking around. He was still holding Ginny in his arms, though he looked more tired than he had three levels up.

"It doesn't matter," Harry said. "We're almost there." He looked to his Patronus, who regarded him with apparent calm. "You know what I'm going to do, don't you?"

"Of course," the Patronus answered. "I am you, after all. And I agree, this recourse has been long overdue."

Harry nodded and turned back to the block door, pointing his wand at the padlock. It snapped open and Harry pulled it from the latch, throwing it across the floor. He pulled the door open and he, Sirius with Ginny, and his Patronus marched the length of the block to the far wall.

This was the inner wall of Azkaban; on the other side was the Dementor nest, where up to a hundred Dementors would be waiting, wounds in the world that needed destroying.

Harry steeled himself. What he was about to do would be difficult, the most difficult single thing he had ever done. One Dementor 25 years ago was one thing; 100 of them all at once would be quite another. And it would be only after he had expended magic getting through the great steel inner wall, six inches or more thick. He put the wand he held against the steel wall and imagined a thin ring of the material Transfiguring to oil. This was partial Transfiguration, a skill he had created a quarter-century ago, and he was still the only wizard in the world that could do it.

Time passed excruciatingly slowly. There was no way to hurry it along, it depended on his concentration and that was hard to come by in this place, though the presence of his Patronus, standing patiently beside him, helped.

Sirius wasn't so patient, however. "How much longer?" he asked, his voice a low growl. "They've got to be coming for us any minute now!"

"They are," the Patronus said without looking at Sirius. "They are two levels above us and moving as quickly as they can. They will reach this level in perhaps another minute."

"Not much longer," Harry muttered, feeling the metal he was transforming begin to react with his magic. "The plug will fall into the central core, I've angled the edges downward so it will slide loose. And then —"

Well, what would they do then? After Harry took care of the Dementors they would have to move onto the Dementors' nest, where no wards preventing exit from the prison could be active, and create a Portkey that would take them out of here. But where would they go? Harry hadn't really thought that far ahead yet.

The Patronus suddenly turned to face the other end of the block. "Aurors are about to enter this level," it said, calmly. "Harry, you will have to lock the block door —"

"I can't," Harry said. "I'd have to restart this Transfiguration!"

"Hell," Sirius snarled, placing Ginny on the floor. "Keep going, Harry, I'll take care of the Aurors!" He turned and ran unsteadily toward the far end of the cell block.

A ring of dark liquid suddenly appeared in the metal wall, and the circle of metal began sliding away from Harry. It slipped out of the hole and fell, but before it fell out of view it hit bottom and tipped forward, landing with a large splat in a combination of mud and ash. There was a whirl of dozen of black, tattered cloaks as Dementors moved out of the metal cylinder's path.

Behind Harry were growls and shouts of surprise and alarm, but he dared not turn his attention away from the Dementors. "Go," he said to his Patronus, his voice shaking. "Give them the Death they deserve." It moved forward, past him and into the central core of Azkaban, shining brighter and brighter as Harry's anger was finally released. A sun suddenly blossomed, whiting out everything else from view. Harry held a hand in front of his eyes, noting as he did so that he could see the bones of his hand through his flesh and his eyelids, so bright was his Patronus.

When the brightness faded, Harry's Patronus was gone, but so was the sensation of despair and helplessness that the Patronus had held at bay, and Harry leaned forward through the hole in the wall, seeing nothing in the central core but tattered rags covering a mound of dirt and mud. He looked upward, seeing a triangle of blue far above him; other rags floated high above, but Harry couldn't tell if they were the remains of Dementors or some who had escaped. Either way, they were gone.

There was a groan from the other end of the block. Harry ran toward it, finding Sirius on his hands and knees surrounded by three unconscious Aurors. There was a wand in his hand, apparently taken from one of the Aurors. He looked up at Harry as Harry bent down next to him.

"I guess I've still got it," Sirius croaked as Harry helped him to his feet. "Of course it didn't hurt that they didn't expect a large dog to jump them as they tried to break in here."

"Are you alright?" Harry asked, examining him. Sirius didn't seem harmed except for the knife wound in his side, where Pettigrew had stabbed him.

"Never better," Sirius grinned crookedly. "Can we get the hell out of here now? Did you scare the Dementors off?" He looked through the hole in the wall, then back at Harry, his face white. "Harry, what the hell did you do?"

"I destroyed them," Harry told him. "Like I said I would."

"Merlin's pants," Sirius said, staring in wonder at the empty cloaks fluttering about in the now-empty core of Azkaban. "I wouldn't have believed it if I hadn't seen it. I guess we can leave now."

"Yeah," Harry agreed. "I just wish I knew where we should go."

"Oh, I've got that covered," Sirius said, as the two of them moved back toward the hole in the wall. "We'll go to my dear mother's house."

Harry picked up Ginny and he and Sirius stood at the brink of the pit of hell. It was a ten-foot drop to the Dementors' nest. "How do we get down there?" Sirius asked. "I could jump that in my Animagus form."

"Levitation Charm," Harry said. "Think you can lower me and Ginny down?"

"I just beat three Aurors single-handed," Sirius laughed. "A Levitation Charm should be a doss." He pointed his captured wand at Harry and Ginny. "Wingardium Leviosa!"

Harry and Ginny lifted off of the floor and floated out into the central core, where they slowly moved down to rest on the circle of steel that moments ago had been part of the walls of Azkaban. Harry let Ginny's feet down, holding her upright with this left arm, and pointed his wand up at Sirius, invoking the Levitation Charm. Sirius floated down to land next to the two of them.

"Right, then," Sirius said as he took something from his pocket. It was a dragon tooth necklace. "One of Aurors was wearing this," he said to Harry. "I knew we'd need something for a Portkey. Hope I can get this right with a stolen wand," he muttered, then tapped the tooth with the wand, saying "Portus." The tooth glowed blue momentarily.

"Nothing fancy," he said quickly, holding out the tooth for Harry to touch. "It'll go in five seconds. If I've cast the spell right, we'll find ourselves in —"

A hook grabbed Harry behind his navel, pulling him forward motionlessly into a whirlwind of color and sound, and everything went dark for a not-so-brief instant.

=ooo=

Harry's feet slammed (well, slammed wasn't the right word, the ground was just suddenly there) into ground and he staggered, both with sudden disorientation and Ginny's weight in his arms, and he toppled over. He twisted so that Ginny landed on him instead of he on her, and he groaned as her weight knocked the wind out of him. "Ouch," he said, under his breath.

Next to him Sirius, who had fallen over as he reappeared as well, was already getting to his feet. He leaned over Harry, grinning excitedly. "I did it, Harry! We're home!" He reached down and picked Ginny up off him. "Come on, let's get inside before someone begins wondering who we are and how we got here!"

Still holding Ginny, Sirius helped Harry to his feet. The change in his demeanor was remarkable; where he'd been nervous and irritable before, he was now smiling and excited. He led Harry toward one of the houses that lined the square they'd landed in. The house was old — its walls were dirty, the windows covered with dust and grime. They walked up the worn steps and stood in front of the shabby, scratched black door. The only thing on it that appeared new was its doorknocker, which had the appearance of a twisted silver serpent.

"Take her a moment," Sirius said to Harry, indicating Ginny. Harry held her at his side as Sirius took out the wand he'd acquired and tapped the doorknocker once. There were several clicks and a long clatter like a chain being dragged across a floor. The door opened slowly with a creak.

"In we go," Sirius said quickly, taking hold of Ginny so they could walk her inside. "Once we're inside, don't say anything until I tell you it's okay to speak."

What was the big deal about not speaking now that they were inside? Harry wondered, but he kept silent. Sirius waved his wand and gas lamps sputtered and lit, casting dim light along a long hallway of old, peeling wallpaper and rows of old, darkened portraits hung along the walls. The carpet under their feet looked moth-eaten and threadbare. What kind of house was this? Harry wondered. It looked more like some Demented prisoner of Azkaban had tried to fix up a corridor to look like home.

Sirius moved along the hallway, past a pair of dark curtains and a large umbrella stand that looked unsettlingly like a severed troll's leg, then past a staircase that led upward into darkness. Past the stairs was a door, and Sirius led them through it and into a long drawing room. He waved the door shut with his wand, pointed to a lounger where they placed Ginny, then turned and smiled at Harry.

"Welcome to my home, Harry," he said. "Number 12, Grimmauld Place. This was my parents' home until my mother died a few years ago. I inherited it, probably because she never got round to taking me out of my father's will or making one of her own. I left when I was 16. Didn't think I'd ever set foot in the place again, but I guess you should never say never, right?"

"This is your home?" Harry frowned. He could see several problems with this. "Won't the Ministry know to look for you here, once they realize we've escaped?"

Sirius considered that for a several seconds. "I suppose so," he shrugged. "It seemed like a good idea, though, when we needed to get out of Azkaban. My father had a Fidelius Charm placed on the house to keep Ministry people from bothering us, but that was years ago — so many of us became Secret Keepers afterward he died that probably anyone can show up here now."

"A new Fidelius would be a good idea," Harry suggested, "if we can get someone to cast it. We need a place to hide — I can't go home and neither can Ginny."

"I never learned the Fidelius," Sirius muttered. "Too damned complicated for me. I'm better at Charms and Defense magic. D'you know anyone you can trust who can cast it?"

"Hermione could," Harry said, after a second. "But I don't want to drag her into this right now."

"And who's Hermione?" Sirius asked, curiously.

"My wife," Harry said. He gave Sirius a look. "I thought I told you that."

"You told me you were married," Sirius replied. "Not what her name was. Anyone else you can think of?"

"Well — Remus Lupin," Harry said. "But we certainly can't ask him."

"We can't?" Sirius was grinning crookedly again. "Why not?"

Harry shook his head, astonished. "Because he's the Chief Warlock of the bloody Wizengamot, that's why not! If he heard from either you or me he'd be obligated to turn us in to the Ministry!"

"Why don't we ask him?" Sirius said, with a smirk. When Harry just shook his head disbelievingly, Sirius walked out of the room. Harry followed hot on his heels, wondering what he would do. Sirius walked up the staircase to the first floor, with Harry behind him staring with some amazement at the heads of house-elves lining the wall. The Blacks beheaded their house-elves?

Sirius strode down the first floor hallway, reaching a door and flinging it open. He walked over to a dresser and rummaged around in one of the drawers, reaching deep into its depths before withdrawing his hand once again and holding it up toward Harry. There was a small, round mirror in it, and Harry knew immediately what he intended. "Wait a minute —" he said, trying to prevent Sirius from using the device, but Sirius just shook his head and spoke into the mirror.

"Moony?" he said. "D'you hear me? We need to talk."

They waited nearly a minute in silence before Sirius shook his head. "Hmph," he said, sounding disappointed. "He must've thrown it away, or broken it or something —"

"Who the hell is this?" a voice said quietly from the mirror. Sirius looked up, grinning at Harry. Harry shook his head warningly — he'd recognized Lupin's voice.

Sirius ignored him and spoke cheerfully into the mirror. "It's Padfoot, you hairy prat, who'd you think was calling you on this mirror?"

"Right," Lupin's voice was dry. "You know there's a report that you and Harry Potter broke out of your cells and you're roaming the corridors of Azkaban attacking all the Aurors."

"It was only three Aurors," Sirius said. "And we're not in Azkaban anymore."

"Really?" Lupin said. "Where are you?"

Harry shook his head frantically. Don't tell him! he mouthed at Sirius.

"Well, I said I'd never darken the door of this place again," Sirius answered, "but I'm back home."

"I see," Lupin said. "So, why are you telling me all this? You know that I'm Chief Warlock now, don't you?"

"Yeah," Sirius nodded. "Harry told me."

"You know I'm supposed to report the whereabouts of any known criminals to the Auror Department, don't you?"

"Yeah, yeah, I know all that," Sirius said impatiently. "But this is Padfoot, Moony. You remember the Marauders, don't you?"

Silence from the mirror for some time. "That was a long time ago, Sirius."

"Hmm," Sirius frowned at the mirror. "Maybe it was. Maybe I thought what we all had together would last forever. Maybe I'm wrong about that, Moony, but if you're going to turn us in, at least hear me out about what happened that day back in 1981. I didn't kill Peter, he tricked us all. You never got to hear the entire story, and I'm the only one left of all of us who can tell you."

"What happened to Peter?" Lupin asked.

"He came to visit me in Azkaban."

More silence. "He couldn't have, Sirius. The guards would have recognized him and called the Ministry. He'd have to explain why he was still alive when you supposedly killed him and twelve other people."

"He didn't just walk into the place, Remus." Sirius's voice was hard now. "He was playing some kind of game with Harry. Sneaking into his cell as a rat and pretending to be a voice in Harry's head. I heard Harry talking and went to the window between our cells, and I thought I caught of whiff of Peter. You know I have a good sense of smell. I had the Aurors switch our cells so I could wait for him. When he showed up and changed back to human form beneath my cot, I dragged him out from under it. Harry heard him, he knows he was there, too! Then the rat bastard stabbed me and tried to escape and I —"

"Don't say it," Lupin said quickly. He was silent for several seconds. "You're at your parents' home?"

"Yes."

"Is Harry with you?"

"I'm here, Remus," Harry said into the mirror.

"Okay," Lupin said, sounding relieved at hearing Harry's voice. "There was another report, a woman named Ginny Thomas is missing from her cell, too. They believe you and Sirius broke her out. Is that true?"

"She's here with us," Harry said. "She didn't murder those three Aurors."

"Alright, I'm coming to you," Lupin said. "I'll be there in a few seconds and we'll sort all this out. I hope."